<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="75">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00378599</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P04590</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00378599</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2b and Ribavirin After Orthotopic Liver Transplantation in Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis C Recurrence (P04590AM3)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
  <official_title>PROTECT - Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2b and Ribavirin After Orthotopic Liver Transplantation: Efficacy and Safety in Hepatitis C Recurrence Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an exploratory study and is a Phase 3, single-arm, multi-center, open-label study of
      pegylated interferon alfa-2b, PEG-IFN alpha-2b (PEG-Intron) and ribavirin (RBV) to determine
      the sustained virologic response (SVR) at 24-week follow-up to 48 week in subjects after
      orthotopic liver transplantation (OLT) with chronic hepatitis C (HCV) recurrence.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>A Sustained Virologic Response (SVR), Defined as a Plasma HCV RNA Level Below the Lower Level of Quantitation (LLQ) at 24 Weeks Post-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks after completion of up to 48 weeks of therapy</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Number of participants with SVR at 24-week follow up after treatment with PEG-Intron and Ribavirin in post-orthotopic liver transplant recipients with recurrent HCV.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">125</enrollment>
  <condition>Liver Transplantation</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cirrhosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-Intron plus Rebetol (RBV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PEG-Intron plus RBV treatment for up to 48 weeks with 24-week follow up. SCH 54031 PEG-Intron 1.5 ug/kg SC per week plus SCH 18908 REBETOL twice daily (BID) PO with food, dosed as followed: Weeks 1 and 2, RBV Dose 400 mg (2 capsules, 1 AM and 1 PM). At the end of Weeks 2 and 4 of Treatment (tx), a complete blood count (CBC) was performed. An increase in RBV dose was permitted only if the hemoglobin was &gt;10 g/dL. At Weeks 3 and 4, RBV dose was 800 mg (4 capsules, 2 AM and 2 PM). From Weeks 5 to 48, RBV doses could be increased based on subject body weight. For subjects weighing &lt;65 kg, maximum dose of RBV was to be 800 mg (4 capsules, 2 AM and 2 PM), for subjects weighing 65-85 kg, max dose of RBV was 1000 mg/day (5 capsules, 2 AM and 3 PM), for subjects weighing &gt;85 kg, max dose of RBV was 1200 mg/day, 6 capsules, 3 AM and 3 PM).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Combination of (a) pegylated interferon alfa-2b and (b) rebetol</intervention_name>
    <description>Powder for injection in vials and Redipen (50, 80, 120, and 150 microgram strengths), subcutaneous, dose of 1.5 micrograms/kg, weekly for up to 48 weeks
200 mg capsules, oral, weight based dose of 400-1200 mg, daily for up to 48 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-Intron plus Rebetol (RBV)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>(a) SCH 54031, PEG-Intron</other_name>
    <other_name>(b) SCH 18908, Rebetol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects must confirm that all prior medication washout times have been observed.

          -  Subject must be 18 - 70 years of age of either gender and of any race.

          -  Subject must be transplanted for end-stage hepatitis C or fulminant hepatitis C.

          -  Subject must have documented:

               -  persistent HCV viremia after OLT as defined by plasma positive for HCV RNA by
                  quantitative reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR),

               -  A liver transplant performed at least 3 months prior to screening but not more
                  than 3 years prior to screening.

          -  Subject must be on stable doses of immunosuppression for at least 1 month.

          -  Compensated liver disease with minimum hematologic, biochemical, and serologic
             criteria at the (Day 1) baseline visit.

               -  Alpha-fetoprotein value (AFP) less than or equal to 250ng/mL. If AFP greater
                  than 100 ng/mL, patient will need evidence of normal liver (magnetic resonance
                  imaging) MRI and normal chest computerized tomography (CT) scan within the last
                  3 months or during the screening period.

          -  For subjects with a history of diabetes or hypertension, clearance from an
             ophthalmologist has to be obtained prior to treatment start (Day 1/Visit 2).

          -  Subjects with a history of mild depression may be considered for entry into this
             study.

          -  Female subjects cannot be pregnant or breastfeeding and must be either
             postmenopausal, surgically sterile or using 2 methods of birth control.

          -  Sexually active male subjects are practicing an acceptable, method of contraception.

          -  Contraceptive measures will be reviewed with female subjects at each visit. Dual
             methods of contraception must be used for 1 month prior to the start of treatment and
             6 months after treatment discontinuation.

          -  Pregnancy tests obtained at Screen Visit and Day 1 Visit prior to the initiation of
             treatment must be negative.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Pregnant women, women who plan to become pregnant, male subjects whose partner wants
             to become pregnant, and breastfeeding women (during study and up to 6 months after
             study completion).

          -  Subject has used any investigational product within 30 days prior to Screening or is
             participating in any other clinical study.

          -  Prior treatment for chronic hepatitis C post-liver transplant, including but not
             limited to antiviral or immunomodulatory product, any interferon product, or RBV,
             either as monotherapy or in combination.

          -  Subjects with other organ transplants.

          -  Any subject who received a positive hepatitis C core antibody (HBcAb) or HCV positive
             donor liver graft.

          -  Retransplantation of the liver for rejection or graft failure.

          -  Evidence of decompensated liver disease.

          -  Known coagulopathies including hemophilia.

          -  Known hemoglobinopathies.

          -  Known glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency.

          -  Hypersensitivity to alpha interferon and/or RBV.

          -  Co-infection with hepatitis B virus (HBV) and/or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).

          -  Evidence of active or suspected malignancy or a history of malignancy within the last
             5 years (with the exception of pre-transplant hepatocellular carcinoma histologically
             within the Milan criteria, and adequately treated basal or squamous cell carcinoma of
             the skin).

          -  Any known pre-existing medical condition that could interfere with the subject's
             participation in and completion of the study.

          -  Subject is or was a substance abuser. Subjects treated with buprenorphine (Subutex)
             who have been stable for 6 months may be included.

          -  Patients weighing over 135 kg;

        Is participating in any other clinical study(ies);

        Is allergic to or has sensitivity to the study drug or its excipients.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gordon FD, Kwo P, Ghalib R, Crippin J, Vargas HE, Brown KA, Schiano T, Chaudhri E, Pedicone LD, Brown RS Jr. Peginterferon-α-2b and ribavirin for hepatitis C recurrence postorthotopic liver transplantation. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2012 Sep;46(8):700-8.</citation>
    <PMID>22739223</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 7, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>September 18, 2006</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>June 17, 2010</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
