<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="34">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00457418</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P04831</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00457418</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>High-Dose PEG-Intron Pharmacokinetic Study in Patients With Melanoma (Study P04831 AM2)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pharmacokinetic Study of PEG-Intron, Administered Weekly in Subjects With High-Risk Melanoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to establish the pharmacokinetics of PEG-Intron, administered
      at a dose of 6 μg/kg/week for 8 weeks (induction treatment), followed by a dose of 3
      μg/kg/week for up to 252 weeks (maintenance treatment), in patients with high risk melanoma.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Pharmacokinetics Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Curve (AUC) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>AUC was defined as the actual body exposure to drug after administration of a dose of the drug.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Serum Concentration (Cmax) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Cmax was defined as observed maximum plasma concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Average Concentration Within the Dosing Interval (Cavg) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Cavg was defined as average plasma concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum Serum Concentration (Cmin) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Cmin was defined as observed minimum plasma concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Observed Time to Achieve Cmax (Tmax) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Tmax was defined as time of maximum plasma concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Clearance(CL/F) of PEG-Intron at 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, and 24, 48, 72, 96, and 168 hours postdose at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>CL/F was defined apparent clearance - the volume of plasma in the vascular compartment cleared of drug per unit of time and per kilogram of body weight by the processes of metabolism and excretion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Who Experienced an Adverse Event (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Entire study duration (up to 5 years)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>An adverse event (AE) was defined as any untoward medical occurrence or unfavorable and unintended sign in a subject administered a pharmaceutical product, biologic (at any dose), or medical device, whether or not considered related to the use of that product.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-Intron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>6 ug/kg/week, SC (first 8 weeks)
3 ug/kg/week, SC (252 weeks [weeks 9-260], maintenance)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PEG-Intron</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-Intron</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCH 054031</other_name>
    <other_name>peginterferon alfa-2b</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects at least 18 years of age, of either sex, and of any race.

          -  Cytologically or histologically-confirmed melanoma, arising from a cutaneous or
             unknown site of origin, at Stages IIB, IIC, IIIA, IIIB, IIIC according to the
             American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) 2001 guidelines.

          -  Adequate hepatic, renal and bone marrow function within 4 weeks prior to initiation
             of study treatment.

          -  Subjects presenting with synchronous primary and regional melanoma must have had
             adequate surgical margins surrounding the primary lesion.

          -  Full lymphadenectomy must be performed within 90 days prior to initiation of study
             treatment.

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.

          -  Give informed consent according to International Conference on Harmonisation - Good
             Clinical Practice (ICH-GCP) and national/local policy.

          -  Be able to adhere to dose and visit schedules.

          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must be using a medically accepted method
             of birth control prior to Screening and agree to continue its use during the study or
             be surgically sterilized.

          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test
             at Screening.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Female subjects who are pregnant, intend to become pregnant, or are breastfeeding.

          -  Previous treatment with interferon alpha, chemotherapy or immunotherapy for melanoma.

          -  Ocular melanoma, or melanoma of the mucous membranes.

          -  Evidence of distant or non-regional lymph node metastases.

          -  In-transit melanoma, even if the lesion has been resected.

          -  Disease that cannot be completely surgically resected.

          -  Lack of recovery from recent surgery.

          -  Prior malignancy within the past 5 years, except surgically cured squamous cell
             carcinoma of the skin, successfully resected early stage cutaneous melanoma, or
             cervical carcinoma in situ.

          -  Severe cardiovascular disease.

          -  Thyroid dysfunction not responsive to therapy.

          -  Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus (in the opinion of the investigator).

          -  Active autoimmune disease.

          -  Active and/or uncontrolled infection.

          -  History of seropositivity for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).

          -  Pre-existing psychiatric condition.

          -  Clinical diagnosis of substance abuse of one or more of the following drugs within
             the following timeframes (excluding time spent in detoxification, hospitalization or
             incarceration):

               -  Alcohol, intravenous drug use, inhalational, psychotropics, narcotics, cocaine,
                  prescription or over-the-counter drugs: within 1 year of the Screening visit.

               -  Methadone, buprenorphine hydrochloride (HCl), and/or butorphanol tartrate:
                  within 1 year of Screening visit, unless subject has drug screen negative for
                  other (non-narcotic) drugs documented in the past year and repeated negative
                  within 2 months of Screening visit.

               -  Multi-drug abuse (2 or more substances in 16a and 16b): within 3 years of
                  Screening visit.

               -  Marijuana:

                    -  If historic use is deemed excessive by the principal investigator (or
                       medically qualified individual), or is interfering with the subject's life,
                       then the subject is not eligible and should not be screened.

                    -  If marijuana use is not deemed excessive by principal investigator and does
                       not interfere with life, subject must discontinue any current use of
                       marijuana prior to entry into study.

          -  Medical condition requiring chronic systemic corticosteroids.

          -  Known allergy to the drug substance or any of the excipients in the PEG-Intron
             formulation.

          -  Any situation or condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere
             with optimal participation in the study.

          -  Use of any investigational drugs within 30 days of study entry.

          -  Participation in other clinical studies of investigational treatments.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Daud AI, Xu C, Hwu WJ, Urbas P, Andrews S, Papadopoulos NE, Floren LC, Yver A, Deconti RC, Sondak VK. Pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic analysis of adjuvant pegylated interferon α-2b in patients with resected high-risk melanoma. Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2011 Mar;67(3):657-66. doi: 10.1007/s00280-010-1326-9. Epub 2010 May 28.</citation>
    <PMID>20509027</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 12, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 5, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>May 28, 2013</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
