<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00371761</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P04498</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00371761</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PegIntron Versus Adefovir in the Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B (CHB) e Antigen Positive Patients in Taiwan (P04498/MK-4031-278)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label, Randomized, Comparative Study With PegIntron vs. Adefovir in the Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B (CHB) e Antigen Positive Patients in Taiwan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Taiwan: Department of Health</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label, randomized, comparative, multi-center study. Subjects will be
      screened within 2 weeks prior to study entry to establish eligibility. Subjects who meet all
      the selection criteria will be randomly assigned 1:1 to (1) once-a-week, subcutaneous
      Pegylated interferon alfa-2b (PegIntron) (1.5 mcg/kg body weight) or (2) oral adefovir 10 mg
      daily. The treatment phase will be 24 weeks for PegIntron and 48 weeks for adefovir. All
      subjects completing the assigned treatment phase will be followed up for an additional 48
      weeks for PegIntron and 24 weeks for adefovir as observation phase. The primary objective is
      to establish the efficacy profile of PegIntron. Secondary objectives are to compare the
      efficacy profile of PegIntron with that of adefovir, compare efficacy of PegIntron in
      lamivudine-naïve and lamivudine-experienced subjects, and to establish the safety profile of
      PegIntron in treating patients with hepatitis B e antigen (HBeAg)-positive chronic hepatitis
      B.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With a Combined Response Consisting of All Three Responses - (a) Serological Response, (b) Virological Response, and (c) Biochemical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 72 [for Pegylated interferon alfa-2b (PegIntron), at 48 weeks post PegIntron treatment for up to 24 weeks; for Adefovir, at 24 weeks post adefovir treatment for up to 48 weeks]</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Serological response is defined as Loss of HBeAg (Hepatitis B e antigen) and Appearance of anti-HBe (Hepatitis B e antibodies); participant is HBeAg negative and anti-HBe positive.
Virological response was defined as having &lt; 10^5 copies/mL of serum HBV DNA (Hepatitis B Virus Deoxyribonucleic Acid) by real-time PCR (Polymerase Chain Reaction).
Biochemical response was defined as acheiving normal levels of ALT (Alanine Aminotransferase) level in Units/L.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis B, Chronic (CHB)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PegIntron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PegIntron, 1.5 micrograms/kg weekly, for up to 24 weeks followed by a 48-week observation phase</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adefovir</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adefovir, 10 mg daily, for up to 48 weeks followed by a 24-week observation phase</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated interferon alfa-2b (PegIntron)</intervention_name>
    <description>Powder for injection in vials ( 100, and 120 microgram strengths), subcutaneous, dose of 1.5 micrograms/kg, weekly for up to 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>PegIntron</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCH 54031, Peg-Intron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adefovir dipivoxil (adefovir)</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mg adefovir dipivoxil (equivalent to 5.4.5 mg adefovir) tablets, oral, dose of 1 tablet per day for up to 48 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Adefovir</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hepsera</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Adult male or female, 18 to 70 years of age.

          -  Documented positive serum hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) for a minimum of 6
             months prior to randomization.

          -  Hepatitis B virus (HBV) replication and hepatitis documented by:

               -  Serum HBV DNA (Hepatitis B Virus Deoxyribonucleic acid) &gt;= 10^5 copies/mL within
                  3 months prior to entry

               -  Positive serum hepatitis B e antigen (HBeAg) within 3 months prior to entry

               -  Documented presence of ALT (Alanine Aminotransferase) twice (1 month apart)
                  within 3 months prior to entry (2 to 10 folds above the upper normal level)

               -  Liver biopsy finding shows evidence of chronic hepatitis without liver
                  cirrhosis, document acceptable if no anti-HBV treatment within 1 year prior to
                  randomization

               -  Naïve or exposed to lamivudine (3 months treatment-free interval prior to
                  randomization)

               -  Adequate renal function (creatinine within normal upper limit).

          -  Compensated liver disease with certain minimum hematological and serum biochemical
             criteria.

          -  Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) and free T4 within normal ranges.

          -  Negative antibody to hepatitis C and hepatitis D.

          -  Negative antibody to human immunodeficiency virus.

          -  Negative evidence for hepatocellular carcinoma by alfa-fetoprotein and ultrasound
             within 1 month prior to randomization.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Women who are pregnant or nursing.

          -  Prior treatment for hepatitis with any interferon or adefovir, or other
             investigational anti-virus agents.

          -  Prior treatment for hepatitis with immunomodulatory drug within 2 years prior to
             randomization.

          -  Suspected hypersensitivity to interferon or adefovir.

          -  Liver cirrhosis.

          -  History of severe psychiatric disease, especially depression.

          -  Concurrent malignancies (including hepatocellular carcinoma).

          -  Unstable or significant cardiovascular diseases.

          -  Prolonged exposure to known hepatotoxins.

          -  History of thyroid disease poorly controlled on prescribed medication.

          -  Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus.

          -  Have suspected or confirmed significant hepatic disease from an etiology other than
             HBV.

          -  Severe renal disease or myeloid dysfunction.

          -  History of organ transplantation other than cornea and hair transplant.

          -  Any medical condition requiring chronic systemic administration of steroids.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 7, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 31, 2006</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>July 15, 2010</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hepatitis B virus</keyword>
  <keyword>Pegylated interferon alfa-2b (PegIntron)</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Adefovir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adefovir dipivoxil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
