<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="208">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01648140</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>115879</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01648140</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dose Ranging of GSK2336805 in Combination Therapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>HAI115879</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II Multicenter, Parallel-Group, Randomized, Dose-Ranging Study to Investigate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics Following 12 Weeks of Oral Administration of GSK2336805 With Pegylated Interferon and Ribavirin in Treatment-Naïve Subjects With Chronic Genotype 1 or 4 Hepatitis C Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PPD</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      GSK2336805 is a novel hepatitis C virus (HCV) non-structural 5A (NS5A) inhibitor being
      developed for the treatment of chronic HCV infection. This Phase II, multicenter,
      parallel-group, randomized, dose-ranging study will assess the safety and tolerability,
      antiviral activity, and pharmacokinetics of GSK2336805 at 2 dose levels (40 and 60 mg) in
      combination with pegylated interferon alfa-2a (PEG) and ribavirin (RIBA) in approximately
      100 treatment-naïve subjects with chronic genotype 1 HCV infection.

      In a separate nonrandomized single-arm cohort, up to 15 treatment-naïve subjects with
      genotype 4 chronic HCV infection will be enrolled in parallel at the dose level of 60 mg of
      GSK2336805.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subjects with chronic genotype 1 hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection will be randomly assigned
      on a 2:2:1 basis to 1 of 3 treatment arms: T40 (GSK2336805 40 mg and PEG + RIBA) or T60
      (GSK2336805 60 mg and PEG + RIBA) or PEG + RIBA and telaprevir (PRT). Randomization will be
      stratified by interleukin 28B (IL28B) rs12979860 status (C/C versus carriage of the T
      allele), HCV genotype (1a vs. 1b), and plasma HCV Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) (&lt;800,000 IU/mL
      versus ≥800,000 IU/mL).

      An additional nonrandomized single-arm cohort of subjects with chronic genotype 4 HCV
      infection will be enrolled in parallel. A maximum of 15 genotype 4 subjects will receive
      GSK2336805 60 mg and PEG + RIBA. The purpose of this cohort is to further characterize the
      antiviral activity of GSK2336805 in subjects with chronic genotype 4 HCV infection. The
      schedule of assessments for the genotype 4 subjects will be the same as for the genotype 1
      subjects. Recruitment of the genotype 4 subjects may be terminated when the target sample of
      genotype 1 subjects have been randomized.

      Subjects in a GSK2336805 treatment arm who achieve extended rapid virologic response (eRVR)
      will receive a total of 24 weeks of therapy (12 weeks GSK2336805 in combination with PEG +
      RIBA followed by 12 weeks PEG + RIBA). Subjects who are HCV detectable at Week 4 and then
      undetectable at Week 12 will receive a total of 48 weeks of therapy (12 weeks GSK2336805 in
      combination with PEG + RIBA followed by 36 weeks PEG + RIBA). Subjects in the telaprevir
      treatment control arm will be managed according to the current product label for
      treatment-naïve subjects.

      Subjects who complete treatment will undergo follow-up monitoring for 24 weeks after
      completion of therapy. At the end of the 24-week follow-up visit, subjects will have
      completed their participation in the study. The total duration of the study will be 48 weeks
      for subjects who achieve eRVR at Week 12 and up to 72 weeks for subjects who do not achieve
      eRVR at Week 12.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Double Blind (Subject, Investigator), Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of adverse events and absolute values.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessment of 12-week safety in subjects dosed with 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin as measured by the nature and frequency of adverse events and absolute values.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antiviral activity of 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Evaluate 12-week antiviral activity of 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 as measured by extended rapid virologic response (defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA at Weeks 4 and 12).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes over time from predose values for hematology, clinical chemistry, urinalysis, vital sign measurements and electrocardiograms.</measure>
    <time_frame>12-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessment of 12-week tolerability in subjects dosed with 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin as measured by changes over time from predose values for hematology, clinical chemistry, urinalysis, vital sign measurements (blood pressure, heart rate), and ECG parameters.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>GSK2336805 plasma pharmacokinetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and week 4 treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Describe GSK2336805 plasma pharmacokinetics at 40 and 60 mg dose levels when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Very rapid virologic response (vRVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare very rapid virologic response (vRVR) rates defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA 2 weeks after initiation of therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rapid virologic response (RVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare rapid virologic response (RVR) rates defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA 4 weeks after initiation of therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete early virologic response (cEVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare complete early virologic response (cEVR) rates defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA 12 weeks after initiation of therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained virologic response (SVR12)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare 12-week sustained virologic response (SVR12) rates defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA 12 weeks after completion of all therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained virologic response (SVR24)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare the 24-week sustained virologic response (SVR24) rates defined as undetectable plasma HCV RNA 24 weeks after completion of all therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained virologic response rates between GSK2336805 and standard of care</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks after start of treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compare sustained virologic response (SVR) rates among subjects who receive a total of 24 weeks of therapy (12 weeks of GSK2336805 and pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin followed by 12 weeks of pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin) versus those who receive the current standard of care (pegylated interferon alpha-2a, ribavirin and telaprevir based on label recommendations).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resistance against GSK2336805</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (all subjects in GSK2336805 treatment group) and depending on subject's HCV viral load data also at weeks 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 12, 18, 24, 30, 42, 48, Post-treatment Weeks 4, 12, and 24.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Evaluate the potential of hepatitis C virus to develop resistance against GSK2336805 by repeated sequencing of HCV strains. Analysis of the viral genotyping samples will be dependent on the subject's HCV viral load data. All study participants in a GSK2336805 treatment group will have genotypic analysis performed on the baseline sample. Samples from non-responders and subjects who rebound on GSK2336805 treatment will be subject to further genotypic analysis at nadir and at several time points after nadir.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antiviral activity and safety of 60 mg of GSK2336805 in subjects with genotype 4 hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection</measure>
    <time_frame>24-week or 48-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Further characterize the antiviral activity and safety of 60 mg of GSK2336805 in subjects with chronic genotype 4 hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection. GSK2336805 (60 mg) will be given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin for 12 weeks, followed by pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin alone for either 12 or 36 weeks (based on the achievement of extended rapid virologic response).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>GSK2336805 exposure-response relationships</measure>
    <time_frame>24-week or 48-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Describe exposure-response relationships of GSK2336805 for example the relationship between GSK2336805 dose or plasma exposure and measures of virologic response when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of adverse events and absolute values</measure>
    <time_frame>24-week or 48-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Evaluate 12-week safety in subjects dosed with 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin followed by either 12 or 36 weeks of combination therapy with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin based on response guided treatment (RGT) as measured by the nature and frequency of adverse events and absolute values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes over time from predose values for hematology, clinical chemistry, urinalysis, vital sign measurements and electrocardiograms</measure>
    <time_frame>24-week or 48-week treatment period</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Evaluate 12-week tolerability in subjects dosed with 40 and 60 mg of GSK2336805 when given in combination with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin followed by either 12 or 36 weeks of combination therapy with pegylated interferon alpha-2a and ribavirin based on response guided treatment (RGT) as measured by changes over time from predose values for hematology, clinical chemistry, urinalysis, vital sign measurements (blood pressure, heart rate), and ECG parameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">286</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>T40</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype 1 GSK2336805 40 mg, pegylated interferon alpha-2a, and ribavirin arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>T60</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype 1 GSK2336805 60 mg, pegylated interferon alpha-2a, and ribavirin arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype 1 Telaprevir, pegylated interferon alpha-2a, and ribavirin arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>G4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype 4 GSK2336805 60 mg, pegylated interferon alpha-2a, and ribavirin arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GSK2336805 40 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg tablet, round, 10-mm diameter, white to off-white, no markings</description>
    <arm_group_label>T40</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GSK2336805 60 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>30 mg tablet, round, 10-mm diameter, white to off-white, no markings</description>
    <arm_group_label>T60</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>G4</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated interferon alpha-2a</intervention_name>
    <description>180 microgram per 0.5 mL prefilled syringe for single use</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T60</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T40</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>G4</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pegasys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>200-mg tablet, capsule-shaped, light blue, film-coated, and debossed with &quot;200&quot; on 1 side and the logo &quot;3RP&quot; on the other side</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T60</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>T40</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>G4</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ribasphere</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telaprevir</intervention_name>
    <description>375 mg film-coated tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>PRT</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Incivek (United States)</other_name>
    <other_name>Incivo (European Union)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with the
             requirements and restrictions listed in the consent form.

          -  Male or female aged 18 to 70 years of age, inclusive, at Screening.

          -  Genotype 1 or genotype 4 hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection as assessed by Versant HCV
             Genotype assay 2.0 (LiPA).

          -  Chronic HCV infection documented by at least 1 measurement of serum HCV RNA greater
             than or equal to 100,000 IU/mL measured during Screening by the COBAS High Pure/COBAS
             TaqMan HCV Test v2.0 and at least one of the following:

          -  A positive anti-HCV antibody, HCV RNA, or HCV genotype test at least 6 months prior
             to Baseline (Day 1) together with positive HCV RNA and anti-HCV antibody tests at the
             time of Screening; or

          -  A positive HCV RNA test and anti-HCV antibody test at the time of Screening together
             with either a liver biopsy consistent with chronic HCV infection (or a liver biopsy
             performed before enrollment with evidence of chronic hepatitis C disease, such as the
             presence of fibrosis).

          -  Naïve to all HCV antiviral treatment(s), including, but not limited to,
             immunomodulatory and nucleoside/nucleotide treatments for chronic HCV infection.

          -  Agree to interleukin 28B (IL28B) genotyping.

          -  A subject, who, in the opinion of the investigator, is an appropriate candidate for
             pegylated interferon alpha-2a (PEG)/ribavirin (RIBA)/protease inhibitor combination
             therapy for genotype 1 subjects and PEG/RIBA combination therapy for genotype 4
             subjects.

          -  Body mass index &gt;18 kg/m2 but not exceeding 36 kg/m2.

          -  A liver biopsy obtained within 3 years (36 calendar months) prior to the Day 1 visit,
             with a fibrosis classification of noncirrhotic as judged by a local pathologist
             (defined as Knodell less than or equal to 3, Metavir less than or equal to 2, Ishak
             less than or equal to 4, or Batts and Ludwig less than or equal to 2). Both
             incomplete and transition to cirrhosis (e.g., Metavir score 3) are considered as
             cirrhosis. If no recent (&lt;36 months) liver biopsy is available, a study-qualifying
             biopsy must be performed prior to Baseline (Day 1).

          -  All fertile males and females must use 2 forms of effective contraception between
             them during treatment and during the 24 weeks after treatment ends.

          -  Females, is eligible to enter and participate in the study if of non-childbearing
             potential (i.e., physiologically incapable of becoming pregnant) and includes any
             female who has had a hysterectomy or has had a bilateral oophorectomy (ovariectomy)
             or has had a bilateral tubal ligation or is postmenopausal (demonstrate total
             cessation of menses for greater than 1 year).

          -  Females, is eligible to enter and participate in the study if of childbearing
             potential and has a negative urine or serum pregnancy test at Screening and within
             the 24-hour period prior to the first dose of study medication and completely
             abstains from intercourse for 2 weeks before exposure to the study medication,
             throughout the clinical study, and for 24 weeks after completion or premature
             discontinuation from this study or uses 2 of the following acceptable methods of
             contraception throughout the clinical study and for 24 weeks after completion or
             premature discontinuation from this study:

          -  Any intrauterine device with a documented failure rate of &lt;1% per year

          -  Double-barrier contraception (condom, diaphragm, or cervical cap used with
             spermicidal jelly)

          -  Male partner who is sterile prior to the female subject's study entry and is the sole
             sexual partner for that female

          -  Any other contraceptive method with a documented failure rate of &lt;1% per year

          -  Otherwise healthy as determined by the medical history, physical examination, ECG
             findings, and clinical laboratory measurements performed at Screening.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Positive test at Screening visit for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or antihuman
             immunodeficiency virus antibody

          -  History of any other clinically significant chronic liver disease (e.g.,
             hemochromatosis, autoimmune hepatitis, Wilson's disease, 1-antitrypsin deficiency,
             alcoholic liver disease, &gt;Grade 1 nonalcoholic steatohepatitis, and toxin exposures).
             Subjects with Gilbert's syndrome who otherwise meet all inclusion/exclusion criteria
             are eligible.

          -  History of ascites, variceal hemorrhage, hepatic encephalopathy, or conditions
             consistent with decompensated liver disease

          -  Positive results on urine screen for drugs of abuse test at Screening (unless used as
             medical treatment, e.g., with a prescription)

          -  History of alcohol/drug abuse or dependence within 6 months of the study start
             (unless participating in a controlled rehabilitation program)

          -  Screening visit electrocardiogram corrected QT (QTc) interval value &gt;450 ms and/or
             clinically significant electrocardiogram findings

          -  Personal or family history of Torsade de Pointes findings

          -  Pregnant or nursing

          -  Male with a female partner who is pregnant

          -  Abnormal hematological and biochemical parameters, including:

          -  Neutrophil count &lt;1500 cells/mm3 (or &lt;1250 cells/mm3 for African American/Black
             subjects)

          -  Hemoglobin &lt;11 g/dL in females or &lt;12 g/dL in males

          -  Creatinine greater than or equal to 1.5 × the upper limit of normal (ULN)

          -  Estimated creatinine clearance less than or equal to 50 mL/min (as calculated using
             the Cockcroft-Gault formula)

          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), or alkaline
             phosphatase greater than or equal to 5 × ULN

          -  Total bilirubin greater than or equal to 2.0 × ULN (except subjects with Gilbert's
             syndrome)

          -  Albumin less than or equal to 3.0 g/dL

          -  Platelet count less than or equal to 90,000/mm3

          -  History of major organ transplantation with an existing functional graft

          -  Thyroid dysfunction not adequately controlled

          -  History of suicide attempt or hospitalization for depression in the past 5 years

          -  History of any current (within 6 months) severe or poorly controlled psychiatric
             disorder

          -  Subjects who have had a severe or poorly controlled psychiatric disorder more than 6
             months ago but less than 5 years ago are eligible for study participation but must be
             assessed and followed (if recommended) by a mental health professional.

          -  History or current evidence of immunologic disorder; cardiac or pulmonary disease;
             seizure disorder; or cancer or history of malignancy that in the opinion of the
             investigator makes the subject unsuitable for the study.

          -  Treated with herbal or natural remedies with antiviral activity within 30 days of the
             baseline visit or has a history of having received any systemic antineoplastic or
             immunomodulatory treatment (including mycophenolate mofetil, thymosin alpha,
             supraphysiologic doses of steroids &gt;10 mg/day and radiation) within 6 months of the
             baseline visit or expects that such treatment will be needed at any time during the
             study.

          -  Participated in a clinical study with an investigational drug, biologic, or device
             within 3 months prior to the first dose administration.

          -  History of a known allergy to antiviral medications, including telaprevir, pegylated
             interferon alpha-2a (PEG), ribavirin (RIBA), or any excipient in the investigational
             product or history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the investigator,
             contradicts participation.

          -  Requires prohibited medications
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dothan</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>36305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Anaheim</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90017</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>DeLand</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32720</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32806</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>31904</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Savannah</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>31405</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brockton</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02302</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Springfield</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Asheville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fayetteville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jenkintown</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19046</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77074</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Annandale</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22003</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>1070</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liege</city>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sofia</city>
        <zip>1407</zip>
        <country>Bulgaria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sofia</city>
        <zip>1431</zip>
        <country>Bulgaria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sofia</city>
        <zip>1606</zip>
        <country>Bulgaria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Varna</city>
        <zip>9010</zip>
        <country>Bulgaria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon Cedex 04</city>
        <zip>69317</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris Cedex 13</city>
        <zip>75651</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pessac Cedex</city>
        <zip>33604</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Freiburg</city>
        <state>Baden-Wuerttemberg</state>
        <zip>79106</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <state>Baden-Wuerttemberg</state>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuerzburg</city>
        <state>Bayern</state>
        <zip>97080</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13353</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20099</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ponce</city>
        <zip>00716</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Juan</city>
        <zip>00927</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Bulgaria</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 10, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 12, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>NS5A inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>pegylated interferon</keyword>
  <keyword>Genotype 1</keyword>
  <keyword>ribavirin</keyword>
  <keyword>GSK2336805</keyword>
  <keyword>telaprevir</keyword>
  <keyword>Genotype 4</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic hepatitis C</keyword>
  <keyword>hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
