<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="15">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00708500</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P05101</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2007-005151-42</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00708500</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Boceprevir in Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis C Genotype 1 Who Failed Prior Treatment With Peginterferon/Ribavirin (Study P05101AM3)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Safety and Efficacy Study of Boceprevir in Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis C Genotype 1 Who Failed Prior Treatment With Peginterferon/Ribavirin</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study involves treatment with boceprevir or placebo in combination with pegylated
      interferon alfa-2b (PegIntron, PEG2b) + Ribavirin (RBV) (weight-based dosing [WBD]) in adult
      subjects with chronic hepatitis C (CHC) genotype 1 who demonstrated interferon
      responsiveness (a decrease in hepatitis C virus RNA [HCV-RNA] viral load &gt;=2 log10 by Week
      12 or undetectable HCV-RNA at end of treatment) but who failed to achieve sustained
      virologic response (SVR) on prior treatment with any combination therapy of peginterferon
      alpha and RBV. This trial includes three arms, one control arm (PEG2b + RBV for 48 weeks)
      and two experimental arms (PEG2b + RBV + boceprevir). One of the experimental arms, Arm 3,
      consists of treatment with all three drugs for 44 weeks after the lead-in. The other
      experimental arm, Arm 2, consists of all three drugs for 32 weeks after the lead-in.
      Participants in Arm 2 who were undetectable for HCV-RNA at Treatment Week 8 will complete
      treatment at that point. Those who were not undetectable for HCV-RNA at Treatment Week 8
      will receive an additional 12 weeks of PEG2b + RBV + boceprevir placebo. It is hypothesized
      that the addition of a third active anti-HCV drug may lead to more rapid viral response than
      therapy with two drugs, and therefore, the addition of boceprevir to PEG2b plus RBV therapy
      after a 4-week lead-in period may allow for both increased rates of SVR and shorter
      treatment durations (in some populations) than treatment with peginterferon plus RBV alone.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Double Blind (Subject, Investigator), Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained Virologic Response (SVR) Rate in the Full Analysis Set (FAS) Population.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Follow-up Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR is defined as undetectable plasma hepatitis C virus RNA (HCV-RNA) at Follow-up Week 24. This outcome measure evaluates SVR after treatment with boceprevir and PEG2b plus RBV versus PEG2b plus RBV alone in participants with chronic hepatitis C (CHC) genotype 1 who failed prior treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained Virologic Response (SVR) Rate in the Modified Intent to Treat (mITT) Population.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Follow-up Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR is defined as undetectable plasma HCV-RNA at Follow-up Week 24. This outcome measure evaluates SVR after treatment with boceprevir and PEG2b plus RBV versus PEG2b plus RBV alone in participants with CHC genotype 1 who failed prior treatment.
This key secondary efficacy endpoint was added as per the second protocol amendment on 02 DEC 2009.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Early Virologic Response.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2, 4, 8, or 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Having undetectable HCV-RNA at Week 2, 4, 8, or 12 was considered Early Virologic Response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Undetectable HCV-RNA at Follow-up Week 12 and at 72 Weeks After Randomization.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Follow-up Week 12 and at 72 weeks after randomization</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">404</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in Arm 1 (control) received pegylated interferon alfa 2b (PegIntron, PEG2b) + Ribavirin (RBV) (weight-based dosing [WBD]) for 4 weeks followed by boceprevir placebo + PEG2b + RBV (WBD) for 44 weeks with 24 weeks post-treatment follow-up.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, Response Guided Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in Arm 2 (experimental) were assigned either a 36-week or 48-week course of therapy based on their HCV-RNA status at Treatment Week 8.
PEG2b + RBV (WBD) for 4 weeks followed by boceprevir + PEG2b + RBV (WBD) for 32 weeks, then:
36-week regimen: Participants who have undetectable HCV-RNA at Treatment Week 8 discontinue treatment and enter 36 weeks of post treatment follow-up.
48-week regimen: Participants who have detectable HCV-RNA at Treatment Week 8 are assigned an additional 12 weeks of therapy, followed by 24 weeks of post treatment follow-up. Placebo replaces boceprevir for the remaining 12 weeks of therapy, and this switch will occur in a blinded fashion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in Arm 3 (experimental) received PEG2b + RBV (WBD) for 4 weeks followed by boceprevir + PEG2b + RBV (WBD) for 44 weeks with 24 weeks post-treatment follow-up.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Boceprevir (SCH 503034)</intervention_name>
    <description>Boceprevir, 200 mg capsules, 800 mg TID PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, Response Guided Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated interferon alfa-2b (SCH 54031)</intervention_name>
    <description>PEG2b 1.5 μg/kg/week subcutaneously (SC)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, Response Guided Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PegIntron</other_name>
    <other_name>PEG2b</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin (SCH 18908)</intervention_name>
    <description>Ribavirin WBD 600 mg/day to 1400 mg/day by mouth (PO) divided twice daily (BID).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, Response Guided Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rebetol</other_name>
    <other_name>RBV</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Boceprevir placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Boceprevir placebo, 200 mg capsules, 800 mg three times daily (TID) PO.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo+PEG2b+RBV, x 44 weeks</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Boceprevir+PEG2b+RBV, Response Guided Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Qualifying regimen defined as pegylated interferon alfa-2a plus ribavirin or
             pegylated interferon alfa-2b plus ribavirin for a minimum of 12 weeks.

          -  During qualifying regimen, participants must have either a documented undetectable
             HCV-RNA within 30 days of end of treatment (EOT) and a subsequent detectable HCV-RNA
             during follow-up or a documented decline in HCV-RNA by &gt;=2 log10 by Treatment Week 12

          -  Previously documented CHC genotype 1 infection.

          -  Liver biopsy with histology consistent with CHC and no other etiology.

          -  Participants with bridging fibrosis or cirrhosis must have an ultrasound within 6
             months of the Screening Visit (or between Screening and Day 1) with no findings
             suspicious for hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC).

          -  Participants participating in Schering-Plough Research Institute (SPRI) maintenance
             protocols P02570 (NCT00049842) or P02569 (NCT00048724) must have completed the study
             to be eligible for this protocol.

          -  Participants must be &gt;=18 years of age.

          -  Participants must weigh between 40 kg and 125 kg.

          -  Participants and participant's partner(s) must each agree to use acceptable methods
             of contraception for at least 2 weeks prior to Day 1 and continue until at least 6
             months after last dose of study drug, or longer if dictated by local regulations.

          -  Participants must be willing to give written informed consent.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Coinfection with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis B virus
             (Hepatitis B Surface Antigen [HBsAg] positive).

          -  Discontinuation of previous interferon or ribavirin regimen for an adverse event (AE)
             considered by the investigator to be possibly or probably related to ribavirin and/or
             interferon.

          -  Treatment with ribavirin within 90 days and any interferon-alpha within 1 month of
             Screening.

          -  Treatment for hepatitis C with any investigational medication. Prior treatment with
             herbal remedies with known hepatotoxicity.

          -  Treatment with any investigational drug within 30 days of the randomization visit.

          -  Participation in any other clinical trial within 30 days of randomization or
             intention to participate in another clinical trial.

          -  Evidence of decompensated liver disease including, but not limited to, a history or
             presence of clinical ascites, bleeding varices, or hepatic encephalopathy.

          -  Diabetic and/or hypertensive participants with clinically significant ocular
             examination findings.

          -  Pre-existing psychiatric conditions.

          -  Clinical diagnosis of substance abuse of the specified drugs within the specified
             timeframes

          -  Any known pre-existing medical condition that could interfere with the participant's
             participation in and completion of the study.

          -  Evidence of active or suspected malignancy, or a history of malignancy, within the
             last 5 years (except adequately treated carcinoma in situ and basal cell carcinoma of
             the skin). Participants under evaluation for malignancy are not eligible.

          -  Participants who are pregnant or nursing. Participants who intend to become pregnant
             during the study period. Male participants with partners who are, or intend to
             become, pregnant during the study period.

          -  Any other condition which, in the opinion of a physician, would make the participant
             unsuitable for enrollment or could interfere with the participant participating in
             and completing the study.

          -  Participants who are part of the site personnel directly involved with this study.

          -  Participants who are family members of the investigational study staff.

          -  Participants who had life-threatening serious adverse event (SAE) during screening
             period.

          -  Protocol-specified hematologic, biochemical, and serologic criteria: Hemoglobin &lt;12
             g/dL for females and &lt;13 g/dL for males; Neutrophils &lt;1500/mm^3 (Blacks: &lt;1200/mm^3);
             Platelets &lt;100,000/mm^3; Direct bilirubin &gt;1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN).

          -  Serum albumin &lt;lower limit of normal (LLN)

          -  Thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) &gt;1.2 x ULN or &lt;0.8 x LLN of laboratory reference
             range, with certain exceptions.

          -  Serum creatinine &gt;ULN of the laboratory reference.

          -  Protocol-specified serum glucose concentrations.

          -  Protocol-specified alpha fetoprotein range.

          -  Prothrombin Time/Partial Thromboplastin Time (PT/PTT) values &gt;10% above laboratory
             reference range.

          -  Anti-nuclear antibodies (ANA) &gt;1:320.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 24, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 27, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>May 13, 2011</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Treatment failure</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
