<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="236">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01052701</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NA_00023807</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01052701</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Drug Interaction Study With Ribavirin and Abacavir in Male Subjects With Hepatitis C Who Have Failed Ribavirin Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pharmacokinetic Interactions of Ribavirin and Abacavir in Hepatitis-C Mono-infected Male Subjects Who Previously Failed Ribavirin-based Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Nebraska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research is being done to find out whether abacavir (Ziagen®) lowers the levels of
      ribavirin (Ribapak®) in the body of persons taking these two drugs.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Abacavir is an anti-HIV drug that belongs to the class of nucleosides reverse transcriptase
      inhibitors. Ribavirin is a drug used to treat hepatitis C infection. Both abacavir and
      ribavirin are approved by the Food and Drug administration (FDA). The doses of abacavir and
      ribavirin used in this study are also FDA approved.Some individuals who have HIV infection
      also have hepatitis C. It is possible that they may need to take both abacavir to treat HIV
      and ribavirin to treat hepatitis C. Recent studies suggest that abacavir decreases the level
      of ribavirin in the body (in the blood and in cells named peripheral blood mononuclear cells
      or PBMCs). Thus, taking ribavirin and abacavir together could lead to treatment failure for
      hepatitis C. So it is important to understand how levels of ribavirin medication are
      affected when the two medications are taken together.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Pharmacokinetics Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of abacavir (ABC) on Ribavirin Triphosphate (RBV-TP) intracellular concentrations.</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-dose, and 6 and 12 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of ABC on plasma RBV trough concentrations.</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-dose, 6 hours, 12 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ribavirin plus Abacavir Administration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RBV alone administration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavrin</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily RBV alone 400 mg in AM and 600 mg in PM orally with 12 hours between the doses (Body Weight ≤75 kg)
OR
Daily RBV alone 600 mg orally every 12 hours (Body Weight &gt;75 kg)</description>
    <arm_group_label>RBV alone administration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Abacavir plus Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Daily RBV 400 mg in AM and 600 mg in PM orally with 12 hours between the doses (Body Weight ≤75 kg)
OR
Daily RBV 600 mg orally every 12 hours (Body Weight &gt;75 kg)
PLUS
Daily ABC 300 mg orally every 12 hours</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ribavirin plus Abacavir Administration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  HCV-monoinfected male subjects who previously failed RBV-based therapy for hepatitis
             C infection, and are currently not receiving therapy for hepatitis C; at least 18-55
             years of age.

          -  Negative HIV-1 serology documented by any licensed ELISA test kit within 30 days
             prior to study entry.

          -  Positive HCV antibody documented within 30 days prior to study entry.

          -  Negative HLA-B*5701 test documented within 30 days prior to study entry.

          -  Ability and willingness of subject to provide a signed informed consent and comply
             with study requirements.

          -  All male subjects must not participate in a conception process (e.g., active attempt
             to impregnate, sperm donation, in vitro fertilization). If participating in sexual
             activity that could lead to pregnancy, male subjects must take every precaution to
             avoid risk of pregnancy for their female partners by using reliable contraception
             (condom) while receiving study therapy and for 6 months following permanent
             discontinuation of study therapy. Subjects will also be instructed to counsel their
             female partners regarding fetal risk and need for appropriate contraception (e.g.,
             hormonal, barrier) so as a secondary effort to prevent pregnancy even though the
             female partners will not be study participants.

          -  Estimated creatinine clearance ≥50 mL/minute, within 30 days prior to study entry

          -  Laboratory values obtained within 30 days prior to study entry:

          -  Hgb within the normal limits as defined by the reporting laboratory

          -  AST (SGOT), ALT (SGPT), and alkaline phosphatase &gt;5 x ULN as defined by the reporting
             laboratory.

          -  Direct bilirubin ≤1.5 x UNL as defined by the reporting laboratory.

          -  Subject has not consumed alcohol in the 48 hours prior to the administration of study
             drugs.

          -  Framingham cardiovascular disease risk score &lt;10%.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  As determined by the investigator, a significant active or previous history of
             cardiovascular, renal, hematologic, neurologic, gastrointestinal, psychiatric,
             endocrine, or immunologic disease (s). This inclusive of chronic illnesses such as
             hypertension, coronary artery disease, arthritis, diabetes, any chronic
             gastrointestinal condition that may affect drug absorption. History of chronic or
             acute medical condition that in the opinion of the investigator would jeopardize
             safety of subjects participating in this study. Any other medical or psychological
             condition that might, in the opinion of the site investigator, interfere with
             participation in the study or put subjects at undue risk.

          -  History of anemia, hemoglobinopathy or any other cause of or tendency to hemolysis.

          -  History of RBV-induced anemia that required dose reduction or discontinuation of RBV
             therapy while receiving treatment for hepatitis C infection in the past. Patients who
             required treatment with erythropoietin or blood transfusion for the management of
             RBV-associated anemia will be excluded from participating in the study.

          -  Use of prescription or over-the-counter medications, including herbal products,
             within 30 days prior to study entry that in the opinion of the investigator would
             preclude study participation.

          -  Men with a pregnant female partner.

          -  Active drug use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator, would
             interfere with adherence to study requirements, and/or currently receiving methadone
             replacement therapy for the treatment of substance abuse.

          -  Inability of abstaining from alcohol-containing beverages for the duration of the
             study.

          -  Hospitalization or therapy for serious illness within 30 days prior to study entry as
             judged by the investigator.

          -  Known or suspected HSR to study drugs or their formulations.

          -  Participation in any investigational drug study within 30 days prior to study entry.

          -  Active or history of gout disease.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adriana Andrade, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christine Radebaugh, RN</last_name>
    <email>cradeba1@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Yavette Morton</last_name>
    <phone>(410) 955-1201</phone>
    <email>ygoldsb1@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Drug Development Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Adriana Andrade, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Sulkowksi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Craig Hendrix, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Courtney Fletcher, PharmD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2010</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 22, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 19, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Adriana Andrade, MD, MPH</name_title>
    <organization>Johns Hopkins University</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Abacavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
