<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="8">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00500578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ID03-0010</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00500578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intermittent Use of Aerosolized Ribavirin for Treatment of RSV</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Study Evaluating Two Different Schedules of Aerosolized Ribavirin For Treatment of RSV Upper Respiratory Infections in Patients With Hematological Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ICN Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives:

        1. To determine whether aerosolized ribavirin is effective when given at an intermittent
           dose over 3 hours every 8 hours for therapy of RSV upper respiratory tract infection
           (URI) and whether it can prevent progression to pneumonia.

        2. To determine the effect of this regimen on persistence of viral shedding.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ribavirin is the drug that is normally given to treat upper respiratory infections caused by
      RSV. The drug is only effective when inhaled as an aerosol. This treatment requires the
      patient to be in a tent and inhale the medication. The usual method for administering this
      drug has been to inhale the medication continuously over 18 hours. In this study, the same
      total dose of the medication will be used, however, treatment will be for 3 hours every 8
      hours.

      As part of your standard care, before treatment you will have blood drawn (around 2
      teaspoons) for routine blood tests. You will have a washing from your throat and nose
      collected. For this procedure, around 1 teaspoon of saline will be sprayed into each nostril
      and you will blow your nose into a cup. You will have a swab of the nose and throat. You
      will also have a chest x-ray to check on the status of the disease. Women who are able to
      have children must have a negative blood or urine pregnancy test.

      Before treatment, you will be randomly assigned (as in the toss of a coin) to one of two
      groups. Participants in one group will receive treatment with ribavirin over 3 hours every 8
      hours. Participants in the other group will receive treatment using the standard treatment
      schedule, ribavirin over 18 hours every 24 hours.

      For both groups, the drug will be administered as an aerosol using a face mask. This will
      require you to be in a tent while you are receiving therapy. Treatment will last between 5
      and 10 days. This will require hospitalization. In addition to ribavirin treatment, you will
      also receive Xopenex inhalation therapy every 6 - 8 hours. Xopenex is a drug designed to
      make breathing easier. We may need to use another breathing treatment, albuterol inhalation
      therapy for one time if needed, directly after receiving ribavirin to make breathing easier.

      Every 2-4 days during treatment you will have blood collected (around 2 teaspoons) for
      routine tests. On Days 3 and 7 of treatment (+/- 2 days), you will have a repeat throat and
      nose washings/swabs. The washings and swabs will then be repeated once a week for 2 weeks,
      or until 2 consecutive cultures are negative, if that occurs sooner. If your doctor feels it
      is necessary, you may have a repeat chest x-ray.

      If at any time you develop signs of pneumonia, you will be removed from the study and will
      be treated with the standard schedule of ribavirin by continuous inhalation and/or other
      therapy for 18 hours a day. Also, if you develop any intolerable side effects, you will be
      taken off the study and your doctor will discuss other treatment options with you.

      This is an investigational study. Ribavirin is FDA approved and is commercially available.
      However, the method of administration of ribavirin is investigational. Up to 50 patients
      will participate in this study. All will be enrolled at M. D. Anderson.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrences of Pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Treatment failure defined as progression to pneumonia within 7 days of initial treatment with aerosolized ribavirin. Patients considered as a failure or to have an unfavorable response if there develop signs and symptoms of pneumonia during therapy either evidenced by chest-xray or clinically, meaning they did reach the primary endpoint.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">51</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematological Malignancies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1: Standard Schedule - Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Aerosolized Ribavirin 6 grams over 18 hours every 24 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2: Modified Schedule - Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Aerosolized Ribavirin 2 grams over 3 hours every 8 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Arm 1 = 6 Grams Over 18 hours Every 24 Hours</description>
    <arm_group_label>1: Standard Schedule - Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Virazole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Arm 2 = 2 Grams Over 3 Hours Every 8 Hours.</description>
    <arm_group_label>2: Modified Schedule - Ribavirin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Virazole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients with these underlying malignancies will be eligible for this study:
             Autologous BMT patients, Allogeneic BMT patients, and patients with hematological
             malignancy.

          2. Patients must be at least 5 years of age.

          3. Only patients with infection limited to the URT will be eligible for entry on study

          4. Patients will be eligible for entry on study if a nasopharyngeal wash or throat swab
             specimen is positive by rapid RSV antigen testing or by a positive culture for RSV.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients with evidence of RSV LRTI as documented by a positive rapid RSV antigen
             testing or by a positive culture for RSV from a nasopharyngeal wash or throat swab
             AND new infiltrates on chest radiograph and/or abnormal blood gas determination

          2. Patients with hypersensitivity to ribavirin or its components

          3. Pregnant women. Participants must practice birth control during the study if they are
             sexually active. If the participant is pregnant, she may not be enrolled on this
             study. Mothers should refrain from breast-feeding during the study to avoid injury to
             their children.

          4. Patients with positive RSV by rapid testing or culture in bronchoalveolar lavage
             regardless of the chest radiographic results.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roy F. Chemaly, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>U.T.M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>The University of Texas M.D.Anderson Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 27, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 10, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>June 1, 2010</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hematological Malignancies</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory Syncytial Virus</keyword>
  <keyword>RSV</keyword>
  <keyword>Ribavirin</keyword>
  <keyword>Virazole</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
