<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="168">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02613403</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3682-021</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2015-001483-19</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02613403</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of MK-3682B (MK-5172 + MK-3682 + MK-8408) Fixed Dose Combination in Chronic HCV Participants Failing Prior Antiviral Treatment (MK-3682-021)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Randomized, Open-Label Clinical Trial to Study the Efficacy and Safety of the Combination Regimen of MK-3682B (MK-5172 + MK-3682 + MK-8408 Fixed Dose Combination (FDC)) in Subjects With Chronic HCV GT1 or GT3 Infection Who Have Failed a Direct Acting Antiviral Regimen</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, multicenter, open-label trial of the combination regimen of MK-5172
      (grazoprevir [GZR]) (100 mg), MK-3682 (450 mg) and MK-8408 (60 mg) for 16 weeks with
      ribavirin (RBV) or 24 weeks without RBV in cirrhotic (C) or non-cirrhotic (NC) hepatitis C
      virus (HCV) genotype (GT) 1 or GT3-infected participants who have previously failed a
      direct-acting antiviral regimen (DAA). The combination regimen will be administered as two
      fixed-dose combination (FDC) tablets, referred to as MK-3682B, given once-daily.

      The study will evaluate the efficacy of the combination regimen of MK-5172 (GZR), MK-3682
      and MK-8408 with or without ribavirin as assessed by the proportion of participants
      achieving Sustained Virologic Response 12 weeks (SVR12) after the end of all study therapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prior to enrollment of GT3-infected subjects, the safety and efficacy data for GT3 subjects
      being dosed in Part B of MK-3682-012 (NCT02332720) will be reviewed. Participants in
      MK-5172-017 (NCT01667081) are eligible for enrollment in the study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Sustained Virologic Response 12 Weeks After The End of Study Therapy (SVR12)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after the end of study therapy: Week 28 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; Week 36 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced at least one adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who discontinued study drug due to an adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups and up to Week 24 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced at least one serious adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced at least one drug-related adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced at least one serious and drug-related adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced at least one laboratory adverse event of interest</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who experienced AST/ALT &gt;5 x upper limit normal at Week 4 or later</measure>
    <time_frame>From Week 4 up to Week 40 for MK-3682B + RBV Groups; from Week 4 up to Week 48 for MK-3682B Groups</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>Digestive System Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Flaviviridae Infections</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis, Viral, Human</condition>
  <condition>Liver Diseases</condition>
  <condition>RNA Virus Infections</condition>
  <condition>Virus Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 SOF/LDV failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT1 participants previously failing a sofosbuvir (SOF)/ledipasvir (LDV) DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily + RBV twice daily for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 SOF/LDV failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT1 participants previously failing an SOF/LDV DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily for 24 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 GZR/EBR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT1 participants previously failing an MK-5172/MK-8742 (GZR/elbasvir [EBR]) DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily + RBV twice daily for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 GZR/EBR failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT1 participants previously failing an MK-5172/MK-8742 (GZR/EBR) DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily for 24 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT3 SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, SOF/PR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT3 participants previously failing an SOF/LDV, SOF/daclatasvir (DCV), SOF/RBV, or SOF/pegylated interferon and ribavirin (PR) DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily + RBV twice daily for 16 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GT3 SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, SOF/PR failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>C or NC HCV GT3 participants previously failing an SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, or SOF/PR DAA regimen will receive treatment with MK-3682B (MK-5172 [50 mg] + MK-3682 [225 mg] + MK-8408 [30 mg] FDC) 2 tablets once daily for 24 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MK- 3682B</intervention_name>
    <description>Two MK- 3682B 1,136 mg FDC tablets each containing 50 mg MK-5172 (GZR), 225 mg MK-3682 (formerly IDX21437), and 30 mg MK-8408 taken once daily by mouth.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 SOF/LDV failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 SOF/LDV failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 GZR/EBR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 GZR/EBR failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT3 SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, SOF/PR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT3 SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, SOF/PR failures: MK-3682B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Two to three Ribavirin 200 mg (800 or 1000 or 1200 or 1400 mg total daily dose) capsules taken twice daily by mouth as part of a weight-based dosing regimen.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 SOF/LDV failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT1 GZR/EBR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>GT3 SOF/LDV, SOF/DCV, SOF/RBV, SOF/PR failures: MK-3682B + RBV</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Has HCV RNA ≥ 10,000 IU/mL in peripheral blood at enrollment.

          -  Has documented chronic HCV GT1 or HCV GT3 infection (with no evidence of non-typeable
             or mixed genotype)

          -  Has documented relapse, defined as having HCV RNA target not detected at
             end-of-treatment, but HCV RNA quantifiable during follow-up, after treatment with one
             of the following DAA regimens either by approved dosage and duration or by completion
             of a clinical trial: GT1: SOF/LDV ± RBV; GT1: GZR/EBR ± RBV; GT3: SOF + RBV; GT3: SOF
             + PR; GT3: SOF + DCV ± RBV; GT3: SOF/LDV ± RBV. Participants who previously failed PR
             treatment, with or without simepravir (SIM), boceprevir (BOC), or telaprevir (TPV),
             prior to receiving DAA therapy, may also be enrolled.

          -  Is otherwise healthy.

          -  Has either absence of cirrhosis or presence of compensated cirrhosis.

          -  Is not of reproductive potential or is of reproductive potential and agrees to avoid
             becoming pregnant or impregnating a partner beginning at least 2 weeks prior to
             administration of the initial dose of study drug, through 6 months after taking the
             last dose of study drug (or longer if dictated by local regulations), by complying
             with one of the following: (1) practice abstinence from heterosexual activity OR (2)
             use (or have their partner use) two forms of acceptable contraception during
             heterosexual activity which may include oral contraceptives.

          -  For HIV co-infected participants additional criteria include: 1) documented HIV-1
             infection 2) either not currently on antiretroviral therapy (ART) without plans to
             initiate ART while participating in this study or has well controlled HIV on ART 3)
             at least one viable antiretroviral regimen alternative beyond their current regimen
             in the event of HIV virologic failure and the development of anti-retroviral drug
             resistance.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Is under the age of legal consent, is mentally or legally incapacitated, has
             significant emotional problems at the time of pre-study screening visit or expected
             during the conduct of the study or has a history of a clinically significant
             psychiatric disorder which, in the opinion of the investigator, would interfere with
             the study procedures.

          -  Has previously received a DAA containing regimen other than the permitted regimens
             listed above.

          -  Did not complete their prior DAA therapy due to intolerance to the DAA regimen or who
             failed the DAA regimen for reasons other than relapse (e.g., virologic breakthrough,
             rebound or non-response, non-compliance, lost to follow-up, withdrew consent).

          -  Has evidence of decompensated liver disease manifested by the presence of or history
             of ascites, esophageal or gastric variceal bleeding, hepatic encephalopathy or other
             signs or symptoms of advanced liver disease.

          -  Has cirrhosis classified as Child-Pugh Class B or C or has a Pugh-Turcotte (CPT)
             score &gt;6

          -  Is coinfected with hepatitis B virus (HBV)

          -  For participants with HIV, has a history of opportunistic infection in the 6 months
             prior to screening.

          -  Has a history of malignancy ≤5 years prior to enrollment except for adequately
             treated basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer or in situ cervical cancer or
             carcinoma in situ; or is under evaluation for other active or suspected malignancy.

          -  Has cirrhosis and liver imaging within 6 months of Day 1 showing evidence of
             hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) or is under evaluation for HCC.

          -  Is currently participating or has participated in a study with an investigational
             compound within 30 days of signing informed consent and is not willing to refrain
             from participating in another such study during the course of this study.
             Participants participating in MK-5172-017 (NCT01667081) may be enrolled in this
             study, MK- 3682-021.

          -  Has clinically-relevant drug or alcohol abuse within 12 months of screening

          -  Is a female and is pregnant or breastfeeding or expecting to conceive or donate eggs
             from at least 2 weeks prior to Day 1 through at least 6 months after last dose of
             study drug, or longer if dictated by local regulations.

          -  Is a male whose female partner(s) is/are pregnant.

          -  Has organ transplants (including hematopoietic stem cell transplants) other than
             cornea and hair.

          -  Has history of gastric surgery or history of malabsorption disorders.

          -  Has current or history of any clinically significant cardiac
             abnormalities/dysfunction or personal or family history of Torsade de pointes.

          -  Has chronic pulmonary disease.

          -  Has an hemoglobinopathy.

          -  Has central nervous system (CNS) trauma requiring intubation, intracranial pressure
             monitoring, brain meningeal or skull surgery, or resulting in seizure, coma,
             permanent neurologic deficits, abnormal brain imaging, or cerebral spinal fluid (CSF)
             leak; prior brain hemorrhage and/or intracranial aneurysms (whether adequately
             repaired or not).

          -  Has current or history of seizure disorder unless seizure was &gt;10 years ago, a single
             isolated event, no history of or current use of anti-seizure medications, and a
             documented normal neurological examination at Day 1.

          -  Has history of stroke or transient ischemic attack.

          -  Has medical/surgical conditions that may result in a need for hospitalization during
             the period of the study.

          -  Has a medical condition requiring, or likely to require, chronic systemic
             administration of corticosteroids, TNF antagonists, or other immunosuppressant drugs
             during the course of the study

          -  Has evidence of history of chronic hepatitis not caused by HCV. Participants with
             history of acute non-HCV-related hepatitis, which resolved &gt;6 months before study
             entry, may be enrolled.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 20, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 20, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Flaviviridae Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>RNA Virus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
