<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="54">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01482767</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A5294 (BIRTH)</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>11774</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>ACTG 5294</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>BIRTH</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01482767</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of Boceprevir, Pegylated-Interferon Alfa 2b and Ribavirin in Treating Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) Infection in Adults With HIV and HCV Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Phase III, Open-Label Study of Boceprevir, Pegylated-Interferon Alfa 2b and Ribavirin in HCV/HIV Coinfected Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection is a leading cause of death and illness in people with
      HIV-1. Currently, the standard treatment for people with HIV-1 and HCV coinfection includes
      two drugs—pegylated-interferon alfa 2b (PEG-IFN) and ribavirin (RBV). The purpose of this
      study is to evaluate the effectiveness of giving boceprevir (BOC) together with standard
      treatment in treating HCV infection in people with HIV-1 and HCV coinfection.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For HIV-1-infected individuals, HCV infection is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality,
      and the prevalence of HCV infection is higher among those infected with HIV-1. The current
      standard-of-care (SOC) therapy for HCV infection is treatment with both PEG-IFN and RBV.
      This therapy is 40%-45% effective in patients with HCV infection but is significantly less
      effective in patients with both HCV and HIV-1. This study will evaluate the effectiveness of
      adding BOC, a novel HCV protease inhibitor, to SOC therapy in treating HCV infection
      (genotype 1) in HCV/HIV-1-coinfected adults.

      Participants will be assigned to one of two groups based on previous HCV treatment. Group A
      will include HCV treatment-naive participants who have never received treatment with PEG-IFN
      or experimental agents used to treat HCV, with or without RBV. Group B will include HCV
      treatment-experienced participants who have received any treatment with standard interferon
      or with PEG-IFN with or without RBV, provided the last dose of treatment was 90 days or more
      before study entry. All participants should be on stable antiretroviral therapy (ART) for at
      least 8 weeks prior to study entry using a dual nucleos(t)ide reverse transcriptase
      inhibitor (NRTI) backbone plus one of the following: efavirenz (EFV), raltegravir (RAL),
      lopinavir (LPV)/ritonavir (RTV) 400/100 mg twice daily, atazanavir (ATV)/RTV, darunavir
      (DRV)/RTV 600/100 mg twice daily OR not have received any ART for at least 4 weeks
      immediately prior to entry. Participation in this study will last approximately 72 weeks.

      GROUP A (HCV Treatment-Naive)

      STEP 1:

      Lead In

      Participants will receive PEG-IFN subcutaneously (SC) once weekly and oral RBV daily for the
      first 4 weeks.

      Triple Therapy

      Participants will receive PEG-IFN SC once weekly, oral RBV daily, and oral BOC every 8 hours
      for an additional 24 weeks.

      At Week 28, after completion of Step 1, Group A participants with undetectable HCV RNA at
      Week 8 and without cirrhosis at study screening will discontinue study treatment;
      participants with detectable or missing viral HCV viral load at Week 8 will continue to Step
      2.

      All study drugs must be stopped if HCV RNA is 100 international units (IU)/mL or greater at
      Week 12 or detectable at Week 24 or there is a confirmed increase to more than 1000 IU/mL at
      any time after Week 12.

      STEP 2:

      Participants without cirrhosis at study screening:

      Participants will receive PEG-IFN SC once weekly, oral RBV daily, and oral BOC every 8 hours
      for an additional 8 weeks (to Week 36) followed by PEG-IFN SC once weekly plus oral RBV
      daily for 12 weeks (to Week 48).

      Participants with cirrhosis at study screening:

      Participants will receive PEG-IFN SC once weekly, oral RBV daily, and oral BOC every 8 hours
      for an additional 20 weeks (to Week 48).

      GROUP B (HCV Treatment-Experienced)

      All participants will receive PEG-IFN SC once weekly and oral RBV daily for the first 4
      weeks.

      Participants without cirrhosis at study screening will then receive PEG-IFN SC once weekly,
      oral RBV daily, and oral BOC every 8 hours for 32 weeks (to Week 36); followed by PEG-IFN SC
      once weekly and oral RBV daily for 12 weeks (to Week 48).

      Participants with cirrhosis at study screening will receive triple therapy for 44 weeks
      (Week 5 to Week 48).

      All participants will have study visits at screening and at Weeks 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 16,
      20, and 24. Select participants may also have study visits on Weeks 28, 40, 52, 60, and 72
      or at Weeks 28, 32, 36, 40, 44, 48, 60, and 72. At each visit, participants will undergo a
      physical examination and blood collection. Participants will also complete an HCV treatment
      adherence questionnaire. At select visits, participants will undergo urine collection and
      pregnancy testing (for women of reproductive potential). Plasma, serum, and peripheral blood
      mononuclear cells (PBMCs) will be stored for use in future studies.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained Virological Response (SVR) defined as undetectable HCV RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at 24 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade 3 or higher signs and symptoms and laboratory abnormalities and other serious adverse events (AEs) during the study</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through Week 72</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Undetectable HCV RNA discontinuation (SVR12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Weeks 4, 8, 12, and at 12 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline HIV-1 viral load and changes from baseline at each post-entry visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through Week 72</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline CD4+ T-cell count and changes from baseline at each post-entry visit</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through Week 72</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline fibrosis stage, race, gender, insulin sensitivity, and HCV viral load level</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Undetectable HCV RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Weeks 16, 20, 24, and 28</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade 2 or higher signs and symptoms and laboratory abnormalities and other serious AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Week 28</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">262</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Naive (Group A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group A will include HCV treatment-naive participants who have never received treatment with PEG-IFN, or experimental agents used to treat HCV, with or without RBV. Participants will receive PEG-IFN and RBV followed by triple therapy with PEG-IFN, RBV, and BOC until Week 36 or until the end of the study treatment duration (Week 48). Participants who stop triple therapy at Week 36 will receive an additional 12 weeks of PEG-IFN and RBV (until Week 48). Some participants will discontinue study treatment at Week 28.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Experienced (Group B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Group B will include participants who have received any treatment with standard interferon or PEG-IFN with or without RBV, provided the last dose of treatment was 90 days or more before study entry. Participants will receive PEG-IFN and RBV followed by triple therapy with PEG-IFN, RBV, and BOC until Week 36 or until the end of the study treatment duration (Week 48). Participants who stop triple therapy at Week 36 will receive an additional 12 weeks PEG-IFN and RBV (until Week 48).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated-Interferon Alfa 2b (PEG-IFN)</intervention_name>
    <description>Week 1 through Week 48: 1.5 mcg/kg SC once a week (based on participant's weight at entry).</description>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Naive (Group A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Experienced (Group B)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin (RBV)</intervention_name>
    <description>Week 1 through Week 48: 800-1400 mg orally per day with food (based on participant's weight at entry).</description>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Naive (Group A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Experienced (Group B)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Boceprevir (BOC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 800 mg orally every 8 hours with food at Week 5 through Week 36 or through Week 48.</description>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Naive (Group A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HCV Treatment-Experienced (Group B)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (Groups A and B):

          -  Men and women 18 years of age or older

          -  Presence of chronic HCV infection, defined by presence of plasma or serum HCV RNA in
             a participant with HCV antibody for at least 180 days, two documented HCV RNA
             positive results greater than 180 days apart, or positive HCV RNA with biopsy
             demonstrating chronic hepatitis. More information on this criterion can be found in
             the protocol.

          -  Serum or plasma HCV RNA level 10,000 IU/mL or greater obtained within 42 days prior
             to study entry by any laboratory that has a Clinical Laboratory Improvement
             Amendments (CLIA) certification or its equivalent. NOTE: This must be a quantitative
             HCV RNA test, not a qualitative HCV RNA test.

          -  Screening HCV genotype 1 performed within 6 months prior to study entry from a
             College of American Pathologists (CAP)/CLIA-approved laboratory. Screening genotype
             test MUST BE performed locally; ONLY IF IT IS NOT AVAILABLE LOCALLY can it be done at
             the designated virology specialty laboratory (VSL) (see A5294 Laboratory Processing
             Chart [LPC] in protocol).

          -  Liver biopsy or HCV FibroSURE™ test within 104 weeks prior to study entry with
             interpretation consistent with chronic HCV infection. If a liver biopsy HCV
             FibroSURE™ test has not been performed within 104 weeks prior to study entry, then
             either a biopsy or HCV FibroSURE™ test must be obtained prior to enrollment. The
             cut-off value for the FibroSURE™ test is 0.74, where greater than 0.74 is interpreted
             as cirrhosis. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol.

          -  Participants should have alpha feto protein (AFP) levels less than 50. If 50 or
             greater, they should have a liver imaging study (e.g., ultrasound, computed
             tomography [CT] scan, magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] showing no evidence of
             hepatocellular carcinoma.

          -  HIV-1 infection, documented by any licensed rapid HIV test or HIV enzyme or
             chemiluminescence immunoassay (E/CIA) test kit at any time prior to study entry and
             confirmed by a licensed Western blot or a second antibody test by a method other than
             the initial rapid HIV and/or E/CIA, by HIV-1 p24 antigen, or by plasma HIV-1 RNA
             viral load. More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol.

          -  Currently not on any antiretroviral therapy (ART) for at least 4 weeks immediately
             prior to entry or on stable ART for at least 8 weeks prior to study entry using a
             dual NRTI backbone PLUS one of the following: EFV, RAL, LPV/RTV 400/100 mg twice
             daily, ATV/RTV, DRV/RTV 600/100 mg twice daily. Breaks in therapy for a maximum of 14
             days will be allowed. Dose modifications or changes in drugs during the 8 weeks prior
             to study entry are permitted unless the change in drug was due to treatment failure.
             Participants not on ART should have no plans to initiate therapy during the first 24
             weeks after study entry. Participants on ART should plan to remain on the same
             therapy for at least 12 weeks after study entry. More information on this criterion
             can be found in the protocol.

          -  CD4+ T-cell count greater than 200 cells/mm^3 obtained within 42 days prior to study
             entry at any laboratory that has a CLIA certification or its equivalent

          -  For participants on ART, screening plasma HIV-1 RNA less than 50 copies/mL obtained
             within 42 days prior to study entry by any Food and Drug Administration
             (FDA)-approved test for quantifying HIV-1 RNA at any laboratory that has a CLIA
             certification or its equivalent. For participants who are not on ART, plasma HIV-1
             RNA less than 50,000 copies/mL obtained within 42 days prior to study entry by any
             FDA-approved test for quantifying HIV-1 RNA at any laboratory that has a CLIA
             certification or its equivalent.

          -  The following laboratory values must be obtained within 42 days prior to entry:

               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) 1000/mm^3 or greater

               -  Hemoglobin greater than 12 g/dL for men and greater than 11 g/dL for women

               -  Platelet count greater than 80,000 per mm3

               -  Creatinine less than 1.5 mg/dL

               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST)/serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT),
                  alkaline phosphatase (ALT)/serum glutamic pyruvic transaminaseless (SGPT) less
                  than or equal to 10 x the upper limit of normal (ULN)

               -  Direct bilirubin less than 1.5 mg/dL

               -  International normalized ratio (INR) less than 1.5

               -  Serum lipase less than or equal to 1.5 x ULN

               -  Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) within normal range, unless accompanied by
                  thyroid profile consistent with normal thyroid function

          -  Female participants of reproductive potential (defined as women who have not been
             post-menopausal for at least 24 consecutive months, i.e., who have had menses within
             the preceding 24 months, or women who have not undergone surgical sterilization,
             specifically hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral salpingectomy)
             must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test with a sensitivity of at least 50
             mIU/mL performed within 42 days prior to study entry

          -  All participants must agree not to participate in a conception process (e.g., active
             attempt to become pregnant or to impregnate, sperm donation, in vitro fertilization)

          -  When participating in sexual activity that could lead to pregnancy, participants must
             agree to use at least two reliable methods of contraception simultaneously while
             receiving protocol-specified medications, and for 6 months after stopping the
             medications. Such methods include:

               -  Condoms (male or female) with a spermicidal agent

               -  Diaphragm or cervical cap with spermicide

               -  Intrauterine device (IUD)

               -  Tubal ligation More information on this criterion can be found in the protocol.

          -  Participants who are not of reproductive potential (women who have been
             post-menopausal for at least 24 consecutive months or have undergone hysterectomy
             and/or bilateral oophorectomy or salpingectomy or men who have documented azoospermia
             or have undergone vasectomy) are eligible without requiring the use of
             contraceptives. Acceptable documentation of sterilization and menopause is detailed
             in protocol.

          -  Ability and willingness of participant to provide written informed consent

        Step 2 Inclusion Criterion (Group A):

        Completion of Step 1.

        Exclusion Criteria (Groups A and B):

          -  Known allergy/sensitivity or any hypersensitivity to components of study drugs or
             their formulation

          -  Evidence of decompensated liver disease manifested by the presence of or history of
             ascites, variceal bleeding, or hepatic encephalopathy. If hepatic cirrhosis is
             determined by liver biopsy (Stage 4 Metavir or Stage 5, 6 Ishak) or by imaging, then
             participants must be no more than Child-Pugh Class A and have a Child-Pugh-Turcotte
             (CPT) score of 6 or less. More information on this criterion can be found in the
             protocol.

          -  Other known causes of significant liver disease including chronic or acute hepatitis
             B, acute hepatitis A, hemochromatosis, or homozygote alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency

          -  Infection with any HCV genotype other than genotype 1, or mixed genotype infection

          -  Uncontrolled or active depression or other psychiatric disorder such as untreated
             Grade 3 psychiatric disorder or Grade 3 disorder not amenable to medical intervention
             that in the opinion of the site investigator might preclude tolerability or safety of
             study requirements. Individuals with suicidal ideation or history of a suicidal
             attempt in the last 5 years prior to enrollment will be excluded.

          -  History of uncontrolled seizure disorders

          -  Serious illness including malignancy, active coronary artery disease within 24 weeks
             prior to study entry, or other chronic medical conditions that in the opinion of the
             site investigator may preclude completion of the protocol. Such conditions may be
             discussed with the study chairs.

          -  Presence of active or acute AIDS-defining opportunistic infections within 12 weeks
             prior to study entry. More information on this criterion can be found in the
             protocol.

          -  History of hemoglobinopathy (e.g., thalassemia) or any other cause of or tendency to
             hemolysis

          -  History of major organ transplantation with an existing functional graft

          -  History of autoimmune processes including Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, severe
             psoriasis, or rheumatoid arthritis that may be exacerbated by IFN use.

          -  Breastfeeding

          -  Male participants with pregnant sexual partner

          -  Use of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) or granulocyte-macrophage
             colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF) within 14 days prior to study entry

          -  Use of systemic corticosteroids, lovastatin, simvastatin, interferon gamma, tumor
             necrosis factor(TNF)-alpha inhibitors, rifampin, rifabutin, pyrazinamide, isoniazid,
             ganciclovir or hydroxyurea within 14 days prior to study entry

          -  Previous use of any HCV protease or polymerase inhibitor

          -  Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the site
             investigator, would interfere with adherence to study requirements

          -  Serious illness requiring systemic treatment and/or hospitalization within 42 days
             prior to entry

        Step 2 Exclusion Criterion (Group A):

          -  Virologic failure as defined in protocol
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adeel A Butt, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kenneth E Sherman, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cincinnati CRS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alabama CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA CARE Center CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90035</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southern California CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033-1079</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford AIDS Clinical Trials Unit CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304-5350</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSD Antiviral Research Center CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ucsf Hiv/Aids Crs</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harbor-UCLA CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torrance</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Hospital CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Denver Public Health CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgetown University CRS (GU CRS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ponce de Leon Center CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30308-2012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IHV Baltimore Treatment CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bmc Actg Crs</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02118</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital Therapeutics Clinical Research Site (BWH TCRS) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital CRS (MGH CRS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Hosp. CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wayne State Univ. CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University Therapeutics (WT) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110-1010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cooper Univ. Hosp. CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Camden</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New Jersey Medical School Clinical Research Center CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newark</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bronx-Lebanon Hosp. Ctr. CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10457</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia P&amp;S CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032-3732</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Chelsea CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10011</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weill Cornell Uptown CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Rochester Adult HIV Therapeutic Strategies Network CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chapel Hill CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke Univ. Med. Ctr. Adult CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cincinnati Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Case Clinical Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MetroHealth CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn Therapeutics, CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Miriam Hospital Clinical Research Site (TMH CRS) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02906</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt Therapeutics (VT) CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Trinity Health and Wellness Center CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75208</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Houston AIDS Research Team CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Commonwealth University CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23298</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington AIDS CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98104-9929</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Puerto Rico AIDS Clinical Trials Unit CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Juan</city>
        <zip>00935</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shire NJ, Welge JA, Sherman KE. Response rates to pegylated interferon and ribavirin in HCV/HIV coinfection: a research synthesis. J Viral Hepat. 2007 Apr;14(4):239-48.</citation>
    <PMID>17381715</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kwo PY, Lawitz EJ, McCone J, Schiff ER, Vierling JM, Pound D, Davis MN, Galati JS, Gordon SC, Ravendhran N, Rossaro L, Anderson FH, Jacobson IM, Rubin R, Koury K, Pedicone LD, Brass CA, Chaudhri E, Albrecht JK; SPRINT-1 investigators. Efficacy of boceprevir, an NS3 protease inhibitor, in combination with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin in treatment-naive patients with genotype 1 hepatitis C infection (SPRINT-1): an open-label, randomised, multicentre phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2010 Aug 28;376(9742):705-16. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(10)60934-8. Epub 2010 Aug 6. Erratum in: Lancet. 2010 Oct 9;376(9748):1224. SPRINT-1 investigators [added]; multiple investigator names added.</citation>
    <PMID>20692693</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fellay J, Thompson AJ, Ge D, Gumbs CE, Urban TJ, Shianna KV, Little LD, Qiu P, Bertelsen AH, Watson M, Warner A, Muir AJ, Brass C, Albrecht J, Sulkowski M, McHutchison JG, Goldstein DB. ITPA gene variants protect against anaemia in patients treated for chronic hepatitis C. Nature. 2010 Mar 18;464(7287):405-8. doi: 10.1038/nature08825. Epub 2010 Feb 21.</citation>
    <PMID>20173735</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 2, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 28, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
