<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="107">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01405560</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7009-045</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01405560</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vaniprevir Plus PegIntron®/Ribavirin in Japanese Participants With Chronic Hepatitis C Who Are Non-responders to Previous Treatment (MK-7009-045)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase III Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of MK-7009 When Administered Concomitantly With Peginterferon Alfa-2b and Ribavirin in Japanese Patients With Chronic Hepatitis C Infection Who Were Non-responders to Previous Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Japan: Pharmaceuticals and Medical Devices Agency</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of
      vaniprevir (300 mg twice daily) given in combination with pegylated interferon alfa-2b
      (peg-IFN) and ribavirin (RBV) in Japanese participants with chronic hepatitis C (CHC)
      genotype (GT) 1 who have not responded to previous treatment. The primary efficacy objective
      is to estimate efficacy of vaniprevir, peg-IFN and RBV for 24 weeks as assessed by the
      percentage of participants achieving undetectable Hepatitis C Virus ribonucleic acid (HCV
      RNA) 24 weeks after completion of all study therapy (Sustained Viral Response 24 [SVR24]).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Sustained Virologic Response (SVR)24</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks after 24 weeks of study therapy (up to 48 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR24 was defined as having an undetectable HCV RNA level 24 weeks after completion of all study therapy. The percentage of participants achieving SVR24 were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With One or More Specific Adverse Events (AEs) of Special Interest During the Study</measure>
    <time_frame>From Day 1 (post-dose) through completion of Week 24 Follow-up (up to 48 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>An AE was defined as any unfavorable and unintended change in the structure, function, or chemistry of the body temporally associated with the use of the product, whether or not considered related to the use of the product. Any worsening (i.e., any clinically significant adverse change in frequency and/or intensity) of a preexisting condition which is temporally associated with the use of the product, was also an AE. For this study, safety parameters or AEs of special interest that were identified a priori included serious rash, anemia (anemia plus haemoglobin decreased), neutropenia (neutropenia plus neutrophil count decreased), bilirubin increased and gastrointestinal adverse experiences (vomiting, nausea, and diarrhea). The percentage of participants with ≥1 specific AEs were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Discontinued Study Drug Due to an AE</measure>
    <time_frame>From Day 1 (post-dose) through completion of Week 24 Follow-up (up to 48 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>An AE was defined as any unfavorable and unintended change in the structure, function, or chemistry of the body temporally associated with the use of the product, whether or not considered related to the use of the product. Any worsening (i.e., any clinically significant adverse change in frequency and/or intensity) of a preexisting condition which is temporally associated with the use of the product, was also an AE.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving SVR12</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after 24 weeks of study therapy (up to 36 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR12 was defined as having an undetectable HCV RNA level 12 weeks after completion of all study therapy. The percentage of participants achieving SVR12 were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Rapid Virologic Response (RVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>RVR was defined as having an undetectable HCV RNA level at Week 4. The percentage of participants achieving RVR were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Complete Early Virologic Response (cEVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>cEVR was defined as having an undetectable HCV RNA level at Week 12. The percentage of participants achieving cEVR were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Achieving Undetectable HCV Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) at the End of Treatment (EOT)</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants were assessed for undetectable HCV RNA levels at the end of all study therapy. The percentage of participants with undetectable HCV RNA levels at EOT were reported along with corresponding 95% Clopper-Pearson exact confidence intervals for each treatment regimen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Change From Baseline in HCV RNA (Log 10)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 2, Week 4, Week 8, Week 12, Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>HCV RNA levels were assessed at baseline (BL) and during treatment weeks 2, 4, 8, 12, and 24 using the Roche TaqMan HCV assay, and transformed to Log 10 values. HCV RNA values below the limit of reliable quantification (LoQ) or the limit of detection (LoD) at any time point were handled as follows (imputations done for computational purposes): values below the LoQ but above the LoD were imputed with the LoQ minus 0.1; values below the LoD were imputed with the value of 0 Log IU/mL. HCV RNA levels below the LoD were considered &quot;undetectable&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaniprevir 24 Week Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive 24 weeks of vaniprevir (300 mg twice daily) with concomitant peg-IFN and RBV treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vaniprevir</intervention_name>
    <description>Capsules containing 150 mg vaniprevir, orally, two in the morning and two in the evening for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaniprevir 24 Week Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MK-7009</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>peg-IFN</intervention_name>
    <description>Open-label peg-IFN alfa-2b at 1.5 μg/kg once per week, administered subcutaneously (SC) for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaniprevir 24 Week Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PegIntron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Capsules containing 200 mg RBV, orally, 3 to 5 capsules, dosage based on the participant's weight (600 mg/day to 1000 mg/day), for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaniprevir 24 Week Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>REBETOL®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:

          -  Japanese participant diagnosed with compensated CHC GT 1

          -  Absence of ascites, bleeding esophageal varices, hepatic encephalopathy, or other
             signs or symptoms of advanced liver disease

          -  Has received and tolerated treatment with IFN-based therapy (IFN α, IFN β, or
             peg-IFN) with or without use of ribavirin, but failed to respond to the prior
             treatment (partial responder or null responder)

          -  No evidence of cirrhosis

        Exclusion criteria:

          -  Co-infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)

          -  Positive hepatitis B surface antigen or other evidence of active hepatitis B
             infection

          -  Any other condition that is contraindicated or for which caution is required for
             treatment with peg-IFN or RBV

          -  Any condition or pre-study laboratory abnormality, or history of any illness, that,
             in the opinion of the investigator, might confound the results of the study or pose
             additional risk in administering the study drugs, peg-IFN and RBV, to the participant
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 7, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 28, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>October 6, 2014</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
