<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="85">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00856024</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P05632</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>BR 002-07</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00856024</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ATHENAS - Retrospective Study of Compliance in Chronic Hepatitis C With Pegylated Interferon Alfa-2b/Ribavirin in Brazil (P05632)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ATHENAS</acronym>
  <official_title>ATHENAS - Retrospective Analysis of Compliance to Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis C With Pegylated Interferon Alpha 2b Associated to Ribavirin Until Week 12 and Correlation With Virological Response in Brazil Health Centers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Brazil: National Health Surveillance Agency</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 4, retrospective and observational, multicenter, national (Brazil), open,
      noncomparative, and nonrandomized study, which does not have visits. This study will be
      conducted in accordance to Good Clinical Practices. The procedure will be the review of
      medical records of patients who have already completed 12 weeks of treatment of chronic
      hepatitis C with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin. This review will take place after the
      subjects have signed the informed consent form authorizing collection of these data. The
      collection of data for virological response after Week 12 will be collected prospectively
      through the review of medical records after the subjects have completed their entire
      treatment and follow-up period.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 4, retrospective and observational, multicenter, national (Brazil), open,
      noncomparative, and nonrandomized study, which does not have visits. This study will be
      conducted in accordance to Good Clinical Practices. The procedure will be the review of
      medical records of patients who have already completed 12 weeks of treatment of chronic
      hepatitis C with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin. This review will take place after the
      subjects have signed the informed consent form authorizing collection of these data. The
      physician will be filling out the case report form with the information contained in the
      medical record. Any dose reduction and/or doses not taken during this period will be
      reported through the case report form. The collection of data for virological response after
      Week 12 (such as virological response at the end of treatment and sustained virological
      response after follow-up period) will be collected prospectively through the review of
      medical records after the subjects have completed their entire treatment and follow-up
      period.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Cohort, Time Perspective: Retrospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of Participants Who Were Compliant to Treatment in the First 12 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>First 12 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The participant was considered compliant if he/she had administered 80% of the doses of pegylated interferon alpha 2b and 80% of the doses of ribavirin that were prescribed by the physician in the first 12 weeks of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of Participants Who Achieved Rapid Virologic Response (RVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>RVR was defined as HCV RNA negative after 4 weeks of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of Participants Who Achieved Early Virologic Response (EVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>EVR was defined as HCV RNA negative after 12 weeks of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">902</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Naïve patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients, from Brazil, with confirmed chronic hepatitis C and who completed 12 weeks of treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin and who previous to this treatment had not been treated with peginterferon alfa-2b.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Re-treatment</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients, from Brazil, with confirmed chronic hepatitis C and who completed 12 weeks of treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin and who previous to this treatment had been considered nonresponders or relapsing to prior treatment for chronic hepatitis C.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: HIV/HCV co-infected patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients, from Brazil, with confirmed chronic hepatitis C and infected with Humman Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) who completed 12 weeks of treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peginterferon alfa-2b</intervention_name>
    <description>PegIntron 80 μg, PegIntron 100 μg, or PegIntron 120 μg. The duration of the complete treatment and the doses of pegylated interferon alfa 2b should have been prescribed according to local guidelines, and according to the investigating physician's orientation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Naïve patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Re-treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: HIV/HCV co-infected patients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCH 54031</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Ribavirin 250 mg. The duration of the complete treatment and the doses of ribavirin should have been prescribed according to local guidelines, and according to the investigating physician's orientation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Naïve patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Re-treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: HIV/HCV co-infected patients</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCH 18908</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with confirmed chronic hepatitis C and who completed 12 weeks of treatment with
        peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin. Patients will come from approximately 65 Brazilian
        sites and should satisfy all inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion criteria.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Must have confirmed his/her willingness in participating in this study, after having
             been informed of all aspects that are pertinent to his/her decision to participate,
             by signing and dating the informed consent form (ICF) approved by the Institutional
             Review Board / Independent Ethics Committee on Research (IRB/IEC).

          -  Adult patients who are 18 years old or above.

          -  Must have diagnosis of chronic hepatitis C confirmed through positive qualitative or
             quantitative PCR (polymerase chain reaction) performed prior to initiation of the
             patient's treatment. This result shall be documented in the patient's records.

          -  Must have completed 12 weeks of treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin.

          -  Patients who started treatment for chronic hepatitis C from the year 2008 or later.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Does not confirm his/her willing in participating in this study or refuses to sign
             the informed consent form.

          -  Did not start the treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and ribavirin.

          -  Patients who have less than 12 weeks of treatment with peginterferon alfa-2b and
             ribavirin.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 4, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 4, 2009</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>October 14, 2011</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
