<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="48">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02349048</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR105963</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>TMC435HPC2013</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02349048</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess Efficacy, Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of Simeprevir, Daclatasvir and Sofosbuvir in Treatment-naive Participants With Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 Infection</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACCORDION-1</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Randomized, Open-label Study to Investigate the Efficacy, Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of 6 or 8 Weeks of Treatment With Simeprevir, Daclatasvir and Sofosbuvir in Treatment-naive Subjects With Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>Canada: Health Canada</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy of 6 or 8 weeks of treatment regimen
      containing simeprevir (SMV), daclatasvir (DCV) and sofosbuvir (SOF) in treatment-naive (not
      having received treatment with any approved or investigational drug) participants with
      chronic hepatitis (inflammation of the liver) C virus (HCV) genotype 1 infection with early
      stages of liver fibrosis or with cirrhosis.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label (participants and researchers are aware about the treatment
      participants are receiving), and multicenter (when more than 1 hospital or medical school
      team work on a medical research) study. The study will consist of a Screening Phase (6
      weeks); an Open-label Treatment Phase (6 weeks for Arm A and 8 weeks for Arm B); and a
      Post-treatment Follow-up Phase (until 24 weeks after end of study treatment). Using a
      staggered approach, all eligible participants will be assigned to 1 of the 2 arms, according
      to their level of fibrosis. Arm A (consists of chronic HCV genotype 1 infected participants
      with early stages of liver fibrosis): participants will receive a combination therapy of SMV
      150 milligram (mg), DCV 60 mg and SOF 400 mg once daily for 6 weeks. Arm B (consists of
      chronic HCV genotype 1 infected participants with cirrhosis): participants will receive a
      combination therapy of SMV 150 mg, DCV 60 mg and SOF 400 mg once daily for 8 weeks. A
      sub-study will be performed at a selected study site, where only participants who will be
      eligible to participate in both the main study and the sub-study will be enrolled.
      Intra-hepatic and plasma HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA) levels; intra-hepatic, peripheral innate
      and adaptive immune responses during the treatment, will be assessed in the sub-study.
      Participants' safety will be monitored throughout the study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Sustained Virologic Response at 12 Weeks After end of Study Drug Treatment (SVR12)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after end of study drug treatment (up to Week 20)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who will have hepatitis C virus (HCV) ribonucleic acid (RNA) less than (&lt;) lower limit of quantification (LLOQ) detectable or undetectable, 12 weeks after the actual end of study drug treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With On-treatment Virologic Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 6 (Arm A) or Week 8 (Arm B)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who will have HCV RNA &lt;LLOQ detectable or undetectable, during treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Sustained Virologic Response at 4 Weeks (SVR4) and 24 Weeks (SVR24) After end of Study Drug Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>SVR4: 4 weeks after end of study drug treatment; SVR24: 24 weeks after end of study drug treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who will have HCV RNA &lt;LLOQ detectable or undetectable, 4 and 24 weeks after the actual end of study drug treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With On-treatment Failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to Week 6 (Arm A) or Week 8 (Arm B)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who have confirmed detectable HCV RNA at the actual end of study drug treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Viral Relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>During follow-up (Up to Follow-up Week 24)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who will not achieve SVR12, with undetectable HCV RNA at the actual end of study drug treatment and confirmed HCV RNA greater than or equal to (&gt;=) LLOQ during follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in HCV Nonstructural Protein 3/4A (NS3/4A), NS5A and NS5B Sequence in Participants not Achieving SVR</measure>
    <time_frame>Screening up to Follow-up Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Pre-treatment polymorphisms in the HCV nonstructural protein 3/4A (NS3/4A), NS5A and NS5B regions in all participants and relevant changes in the HCV NS3/4A, NS5A and NS5B regions in participants not achieving SVR will be described.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With or Without an NS3 Q80K Polymorphism at Baseline Achieving SVR</measure>
    <time_frame>Screening up to Follow-up Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participants who achieve SVR with or without an NS3 Q80K polymorphism at Baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C Virus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Chronic hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype 1 infected participants with early stages of liver fibrosis, will receive Simeprevir (SMV) 150 milligram (mg), Daclatasvir (DCV) 60 mg and Sofosbuvir (SOF) 400 mg once daily for 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Chronic HCV genotype 1 infected participants with cirrhosis, will receive SMV 150 mg, DCV 60 mg and SOF 400 mg once daily for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Simeprevir 150 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Simeprevir 150 mg capsule orally once daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daclatasvir 60 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Daclatasvir 60 mg tablet orally once daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sofosbuvir 400 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Sofosbuvir 400 mg tablet orally once daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  HCV genotype 1 infection and HCV RNA plasma level greater than (&gt;) 10,000
             international units per milliliter (IU/mL), both determined at Screening

          -  Participants of Arm A should have evidence of early stages of liver fibrosis, defined
             by a FibroSURE score less than or equal to (&lt;=) 0.48 and aspartate aminotransferase
             to platelet ratio index (APRI) score &lt;=1

          -  Participants of Arm B should have evidence of cirrhosis, defined by a FibroSURE score
             &gt;0.75 and APRI score &gt;2, OR a previous (historical) biopsy documenting a METAVIR
             score F4. In addition, participants should have absence of esophageal varices or
             presence of small (grade 1) esophageal varices determined by upper gastrointestinal
             endoscopy, and absence of findings indicative of hepatocellular carcinoma in an
             ultrasonography

          -  HCV treatment-naive, defined as not having received treatment with any approved or
             investigational drug for chronic HCV infection

          -  Pegylated interferon (PegIFN) and ribavirin (RBV) eligible, defined as not having any
             contraindication to the use of PegIFN and RBV, in line with the prescribing
             information for each compound

        Exclusion Criteria:

        A. Main Study:

          -  Co-infection with HCV of another genotype than genotype 1 and/or human
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) type 1 or 2 (positive HIV-1 or HIV 2 antibody test at
             Screening)

          -  Any evidence of liver disease of non-HCV etiology. This includes, but is not limited
             to, acute hepatitis A infection, hepatitis B infection (hepatitis B surface antigen
             positive), drug- or alcohol-related liver disease, autoimmune hepatitis,
             hemochromatosis, Wilson's disease, alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency, non-alcoholic
             steatohepatitis, primary biliary cirrhosis, or any other non-HCV liver disease
             considered clinically significant by the Investigator

          -  Evidence of clinical hepatic decompensation or presence of grade 2/3 esophageal
             varices

          -  Any of the protocol defined laboratory abnormalities

        B. Sub-study:

          -  Presence of coagulopathy (hemophilia) or hemoglobinopathy (including sickle cell
             disease, thalassemia)

          -  Use of any anti-coagulant (for example, warfarin, heparin) or anti-platelet
             medications within 1 week of the Screening visit

          -  Any of the protocol defined laboratory abnormalities
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Use link at the bottom of the page to see if you qualify for an enrolling site (see list). If you still have questions:</last_name>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Bakersfield</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Marietta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Lutherville</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Winston Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Knoxville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Arlington</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR105963</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 11, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 22, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hepatitis C virus</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatitis C virus genotype 1</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver fibrosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Cirrhosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Simeprevir</keyword>
  <keyword>Daclatasvir</keyword>
  <keyword>Sofosbuvir</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Simeprevir</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
