<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="509">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01182298</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100159</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-I-0159</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01182298</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open Label Study to Evaluate Chronic Hepatitis C Treatment in Latino Subjects With and Without HIV Co-infection</brief_title>
  <acronym>LATHCV</acronym>
  <official_title>Study to Evaluate the Genetic, Epigenetic, and Proteomic Expression in Latino Participants With and Without HIV Coinfection Receiving Treatment for Hepatitis C</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fundación de Investigación de Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Federal Government</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      -  Peginterferon alfa-2a has been approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA)
           to treat adults with chronic hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection with liver disease who
           have not been previously treated with interferon-alpha drugs (which improve immune
           system response to infection). Ribavirin has been approved by the FDA and is usually
           given in combination with interferon drugs such as peginterferon alfa-2a for treatment
           of chronic HCV.

        -  Recent research shows that Latino whites do not respond as well to treatment with
           peginterferon alfa-2a and ribavirin as non-Latino whites. Various factors such as
           excessive weight, gender, and insulin resistance were evaluated to explain this
           difference, but research suggests that underlying factors related to Latino or
           non-Latino background, possibly genetic and immune differences, may be affecting the
           response to HCV infection and treatment. However, more research is needed on the
           effectiveness of peginterferon and ribavirin in Latino subjects with HCV, and with
           combined and human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) co-infection.

      Objectives:

      - To evaluate the safety, effectiveness, and viral response of peginterferon alfa-2a and
      ribavirin therapy for chronic hepatitis C in Latino participants with and without HIV
      co-infection.

      This is an observational study. The observed treatment is received and managed through their
      primary care.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hepatitis C is a major health problem affecting 100- 300 million individuals worldwide.
      Chronic hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection leads to cirrhosis in approximately 20% of
      subjects over a period of 1-20 years. Hepatitis C is now the most common indication for
      liver transplantation in the United States. infection occurs in one-third of all
      HIV-infected individuals, and the natural history among HIV-1 infected individuals
      demonstrates higher levels of HCV viremia, faster rates of progression and cirrhosis. There
      have been very few studies addressing the lower therapeutic response rates in minorities
      outside of African Americans. A recent study showed that Latino white subjects respond less
      effectively (34%) than non Latino white subjects (49%) given the same treatment even after
      adjusting for various important factors. As the current landscape for treatment of HCV
      changes, it would be important to evaluate factors responsible for therapeutic response in
      Latino patients.

      This is a study to address the genetic, epigenetic, and proteomic expression during therapy
      for chronic hepatitis C in Latino participants with and without HIV co-infection. One
      hundred Latino participants who have evidence of chronic hepatitis C with and without HIV
      who are receiving treatment for HCV will be enrolled. The results of this study will enable
      us to explore reasons for the differential therapeutic response rates with Hepatitis C
      treatment in Latino participants with and without HIV coinfection.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    small number of patients enrolled
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>July 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Cohort, Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Log Change in HCV RNA Levels on Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>first 7 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The primary end point of this study is the the log change in HCV RNA levels on Day 7</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hepatitis C</arm_group_label>
    <description>latino participants with Hepatitis C</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Plasma and serum storage.
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        latino with or without HIV infection undergoing Hepatitis C treatment
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:

        A subject must satisfy all of the following criteria to be eligible to participate in this
        study:

          1. Latino ethnicity. Latino ethnic background will be defined as a geographic,
             historical, and cultural heritage shared among persons from Spanish-speaking
             countries in South and Central America, Mexico, and the Caribbean. Both parents and
             all grandparents of the participant have to be Latino, with Spanish as the primary
             language. Participants have to be white; native aboriginal Indians, Asians, and
             blacks will be excluded.

          2. Age greater than or equal to 18 years.

          3. Documentation of hepatitis C infection by demonstration of a positive test for
             hepatitis C antibody and HCV RNA level of greater than or equal to 2,000 IU/mL.

          4. Documentation of HIV-1 infection in the second group of co-infected participants by a
             licensed enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay and confirmed by a Western blot or by HIV
             polymerase chain reaction positive.

          5. Participants with HIV: CD4+ cell counts greater than or equal to 100 cells/mm(3) or
             CD4+ cell percentage greater than or equal to 14%.

          6. Ability to provide informed consent and willingness to comply with the study
             requirements, storage of blood samples and clinic policies.

          7. Participants must have a primary care physician managing medical problems.

          8. For HIV infected participants, care provided by a primary physician must be
             consistent with the current DHHS guidelines. For those on therapy, HAART will be
             provided by their physician.

          9. Willing to undergo genetic testing

         10. About to start HCV treatment (with or without direct acting agents DAAs)

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:

        A subject will be ineligible to participate in this study if any of the following criteria
        are met:

          1. Unable to comply with research study visits

          2. Have any condition that the investigator considers a contraindication to study
             participation.

          3. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.

          4. Patients with poor venous access
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shyamasundaran Kottilil, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Seeff LB, Hoofnagle JH. Appendix: The National Institutes of Health Consensus Development Conference Management of Hepatitis C 2002. Clin Liver Dis. 2003 Feb;7(1):261-87. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12691470</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Engels EA, Chatterjee N, Cerhan JR, Davis S, Cozen W, Severson RK, Whitby D, Colt JS, Hartge P. Hepatitis C virus infection and non-Hodgkin lymphoma: results of the NCI-SEER multi-center case-control study. Int J Cancer. 2004 Aug 10;111(1):76-80.</citation>
    <PMID>15185346</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poynard T, Bedossa P, Opolon P. Natural history of liver fibrosis progression in patients with chronic hepatitis C. The OBSVIRC, METAVIR, CLINIVIR, and DOSVIRC groups. Lancet. 1997 Mar 22;349(9055):825-32.</citation>
    <PMID>9121257</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 26, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 13, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>April 23, 2014</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Latino</keyword>
  <keyword>HCV</keyword>
  <keyword>pegIFN</keyword>
  <keyword>Viral Kinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>IL-28 Haplotype</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
