<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="14">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00736242</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P04584</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00736242</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post-marketing Surveillance of HIV-infected Patients With Chronic Hepatitis C Treated With PegIntron Pen and Rebetol (Study P04584)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis C in HIV-infected Patients With PegIntron Pen and Rebetol According to German Law (§ 67 Abs 6 AMG)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Germany: Federal Institute for Drugs and Medical Devices</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the study was to assess the safety and efficacy of peginterferon alfa-2b
      (PEG-IFN alfa-2b) and ribavirin (RBV) administered to participants coinfected with Human
      Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and Hepatitis C Virus (HCV). Participants were treated by
      general practitioners in clinical practice as part of the post-marketing surveillance study.
      The study assessed the rates of eradication of the HCV and the rates of serious adverse
      events reported with PEG-IFN alfa-2b (1.5 ug/kg/week) and RBV (800-1200 mg/day) in common
      medical practice in Germany.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this observational, non-interventional study, the time of enrollment and start of
      treatment was the sole decision of the physician. No investigational medicinal product was
      provided by the sponsor.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Case-Only, Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Sustained Virologic Response (SVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From End of Treatment to 24 weeks post-treatment (up to 72 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR was defined as undetectable serum Hepatitis C Virus ribonucleic acid (HCV-RNA) at End of Treatment (EOT) and at the End of Follow-up (EOF).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Rapid Virologic Response (RVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At Treatment Week 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>RVR was defined as undetectable serum HCV-RNA at week 4.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Early Virologic Response (EVR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Treatment Week 1 to Treatment Week 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>EVR was defined as undetectable serum HCV-RNA at week 12 and/or a
≥2 log decline in HCV-RNA levels at week 12 from baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant Study Status at End of Follow-up (EOF)</measure>
    <time_frame>From EOT to EOF (up to 72 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Participant study status was assessed at the End of Follow-up (defined as 24 weeks after the end of treatment) based on serum levels of HCV-RNA.
SVR was defined as defined as undetectable serum HCV-RNA at EOT and EOF, Relapse was defined as undetectable HCV-RNA at EOT with detectable HCV-RNA at EOF, and Non-response was defined as a detectable serum HCV-RNA at EOT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Hepatitis C Virus (HCV)-RNA Negativity During PEG-IFN Alfa-2b/RBV Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From the Baseline Visit up to EOF (up to 72 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>HCV-RNA negativity/positivity was documented at baseline in the medical history (anamnesis), and assessed within the laboratory (lab) at baseline and during treatment by Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR).
HCV-RNA (+) = HCV-RNA positive, HCV-RNA (-) = HCV-RNA negative, HCV-RNA Missing = HCV-RNA data not documented, not applicable, not known, not examined, or missing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)-RNA Negativity During PEG-IFN Alfa-2b/RBV Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From the Baseline Visit up to EOF (up to 72 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>HIV-RNA negativity/positivity was documented at baseline in the medical history (anamnesis), and assessed within the laboratory (lab) at baseline and during treatment.
HIV-RNA (+) = HIV-RNA positive, HIV-RNA (-) = HIV-RNA negative, HIV-RNA Missing = HIV-RNA data not documented, not applicable, not known, not examined, or missing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Cluster of Differentiation 4 (CD4) Cell Count During PEG-IFN Alfa-2b/RBV Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From the Baseline Visit up to EOF (up to 72 weeks)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The CD4 helper T cell count was used to assess participant HIV status and was determined in the laboratory at baseline and during the study course.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With A Serious Adverse Event (SAE) During PEG-IFN Alfa-2b/RBV Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From First Participant Visit (12/30/2005) up to 30 days after Last Participant Visit (12/31/2011).</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>An SAE was any adverse drug/biologic/device experience occurring at any dose that resulted in death, was life-threatening (i.e. placed the participant, in the view of the initial reporter, at immediate risk of death from the AE as it occurred), was a persistent or significant disability/incapacity, required in-patient hospitalization, or prolonged hospitalization, or led to a
congenital anomaly or birth defect.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">232</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-IFN alfa-2b + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants received a combination of PEG-IFN alfa-2b plus RBV according to routine clinical practice and locally-approved product recommendations for a minimum of 12 weeks. No investigational medicinal product was provided by the sponsor.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PEG-IFN alfa-2b</intervention_name>
    <description>Peginterferon alfa-2b administered subcutaneously at a dose 1.5 ug/kg/week, according to the European Medicines Agency (EMEA)-approved labeling</description>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-IFN alfa-2b + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SCH 054031</other_name>
    <other_name>PegIntron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RBV</intervention_name>
    <description>Ribavirin administered at a dose of 800-1200 mg/day (on a weight-basis) according to the EMEA-approved labeling</description>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-IFN alfa-2b + RBV</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rebetol</other_name>
    <other_name>SCH 018908</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects coinfected with HIV and HCV seen in common medical practice by general
        practitioners and clinical doctors at 30 sites all over Germany.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  ≥ 18 years of age eligible for treatment according to the Summary of Product
             Characteristics (SmPC)

          -  Presence of chronic Hepatitis C (with elevated liver enzymes and without
             decompensation)

          -  Presence of HCV-RNA and known genotype of the infecting hepatitis C virus

          -  HIV infection confirmed by positive Enzyme Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA) and
             Western blot and Cluster of differentiation (CD) 4 cell count &gt;200/mL

          -  Treatment-naïve

          -  Platelets ≥ 75,000/mm^3

          -  Neutrophil counts ≥ 1,500/mm^3

          -  Thyroid Stimulating Hormone (TSH) must be within normal limits

          -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL (females); ≥ 11 g/dL (males)

          -  Women of childbearing potential must have a routine pregnancy test performed monthly
             during treatment and for 7 months thereafter. Sexually active female participants of
             childbearing potential must be practicing adequate contraception (intrauterine
             device, oral contraceptives, implanted contraceptives, surgical sterilization,
             barrier method, or monogamous relationship with a male partner who has had a
             vasectomy or is using a condom (+ spermicide) during the treatment period and for 7
             months after stopping treatment.

          -  Sexually active male participants must be practicing acceptable methods of
             contraception (vasectomy, use of condom + spermicide, monogamous relationship with a
             female partner who practices an acceptable method of contraception) during the
             treatment period and for 7 months after stopping treatment.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Contraindications according to the European approval and to the SmPC

          -  Pretreatment of chronic hepatitis C

          -  Liver decompensation

          -  Hypersensitivity to the active substance or to any interferons or to any of the
             excipients

          -  Pregnant woman

          -  Women who are breast feeding

          -  Existence of or history of psychiatric condition, particular depression, suicidal
             ideation or suicide attempt

          -  A history of severe pre-existing cardiac disease, including unstable or uncontrolled
             cardiac disease in the previous six months

          -  Severe debilitating medical conditions, including participants with chronic renal
             failure or creatinine clearance &lt; 50 ml/min.

          -  Autoimmune hepatitis or history of autoimmune disease

          -  Severe hepatic dysfunction or decompensated cirrhosis of the liver

          -  Pre-existing thyroid disease unless it can be controlled with conventional therapy

          -  Epilepsy and/or compromised central nervous system function
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 2, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 30, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>December 21, 2012</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
