<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="238">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02577029</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Heparc-2008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02577029</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of ARC-520 With or Without Other Drugs Used in the Treatment of Chronic HBV</brief_title>
  <acronym>Monarch</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-Label Study to Evaluate ARC-520 Administered Alone and in Combination With Other Therapeutics in Patients With Chronic Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) Infection (MONARCH)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Arrowhead Research Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Arrowhead Research Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Australia: Department of Health and Ageing Therapeutic Goods Administration</authority>
    <authority>New Zealand: Medsafe</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with chronic Hepatitis B Virus (HBV) infection will receive either ARC-520 alone or
      ARC-520 in combination with other treatments such as entecavir (ENT) and pegylated
      interferon alpha 2a (PEG IFN) therapy, and be evaluated for safety and efficacy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, open-label study of ARC-520 based treatment regimens administered to
      patients with HBeAg positive or HBeAg negative immune active chronic Hepatitis B Virus (HBV)
      infection. Eligible patients naive to previous treatment, and who have signed an Ethics
      Committee - approved informed consent, will be enrolled and will receive ARC-520 alone or
      ARC-520 plus additional treatments such as entecavir (ENT) and pegylated interferon alpha 2a
      (PEG IFN) therapy. The study may initially involve up to a total of 72 eligible chronic HBV
      infected patients. Patients in all cohorts will receive a total of 13 doses of ARC-520 at a
      dose of 2 mg/kg. Patients will undergo the following evaluations at regular intervals during
      the study: medical history, physical examinations, vital sign measurements (blood pressure,
      heart rate, respiratory rate, and temperature), weight, adverse events assessment (AEs),
      12-lead ECGs, liver fibrosis testing, concomitant medication assessment, blood sample
      collection for hematology, coagulation, chemistry, exploratory Pharmacodynamic (PD)
      measures, urinalysis, HBV serology, cytokines, Follicle Stimulating Hormone (FSH) testing
      (post-menopausal females) and pregnancy testing for females of childbearing potential.
      Clinically significant changes including AEs will be followed until resolution, until the
      condition stabilizes, until the event is otherwise explained, or until the patient is lost
      to follow-up. For each patient, the duration of the study is approximately 96 weeks, from
      enrolment to last visit. Prior to enrolment there is a 60 day screening period. Addition of
      new cohorts and additional treatment regimens are anticipated for this study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients achieving a 1-log reduction in Hepatitis B Surface Antigen (HBsAg) compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 60</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with HBsAg loss (based on qualitative assay) compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Weeks 52, 60, 72 and 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients achieving a 1-log reduction in HBsAg and achieving a HBsAg level &lt; 100 IU/L compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Weeks 52, 60, 72 and 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to HBsAg loss</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Week 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to anti-HBs (antibody to Hepatitis B Surface Antigen) seroconversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Week 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with anti-HBs seroconversion compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Weeks 52, 60, 72 and 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with Hepatitis B e Antigen (HBeAg) loss and Anti Hepatitis B e Antigen (Anti-HBe) seroconversion compared to baseline (if HBeAg positive at study entry)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Weeks 52, 60, 72 and 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with resistance to ARC-520 compared from baseline to Week 52</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 52</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Resistance defined as &gt; 1.0 log IU/mL quantitative HBsAg (qHBsAg) increase from nadir, confirmed by repeat test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with resistance to the combination therapy from baseline to Week 60</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 60</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Resistance defined as &gt; 1.0 log IU/mL increase in HBV DNA from nadir, confirmed by repeat test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and frequency of adverse events as a measure of safety and tolerability of ARC-520 alone or when coadministered with combination therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 96</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis B</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 administered alone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ARC-520 (2 mg/kg every 4 weeks) for 48 weeks (13 doses).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 with entecavir and pegylated interferon alpha 2a</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ARC-520 (2 mg/kg every 4 weeks - 48 weeks) + entecavir (0.5 mg daily - about 60 weeks) + Pegylated Interferon alpha 2a (180 mcg weekly) - 48 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ARC-520</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 administered alone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 with entecavir and pegylated interferon alpha 2a</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Entecavir</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 with entecavir and pegylated interferon alpha 2a</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Baraclude</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated Interferon alpha 2a</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>ARC-520 with entecavir and pegylated interferon alpha 2a</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pegasys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female, 18 to 75 years of age

          -  Written informed consent

          -  No clinically significant abnormalities at screening/pre-dose 12-lead ECG assessment

          -  Diagnosis of HBeAg negative or positive, immune active, chronic HBV infection.

          -  Must be HBsAg (+) during screening.

          -  Must be treatment naïve: Never on pegylated interferon alpha 2a (PEG INF) and/or
             entecavir (ETV) or tenofovir (TDF); and

          -  Have not used nucleoside/nucleotide analogs (NUCs) within the last 2 years prior to
             dosing on Day 1

          -  Must use 2 effective methods of contraception (double barrier contraception or
             hormonal contraceptive along with a barrier contraceptive) (both male and female
             partners)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Pregnant or lactating

          -  Acute signs of hepatitis/other infections within 4 weeks of screening

          -  Use within the last 30 days or anticipated requirement for anticoagulants,
             corticosteroids, immunomodulators, or immunosuppressants

          -  Use of prescription medication within 14 days prior to treatment administration
             except: topical products without systemic absorption, statins (except rosuvastatin),
             hypertension medications, over-the-counter (OTC) and prescription pain medication or
             hormonal contraceptives

          -  History of poorly controlled diabetes mellitus with a diagnosis of fatty liver
             disease

          -  History of poorly controlled autoimmune disease or any history of autoimmune
             hepatitis

          -  History of heterozygous or homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia.

          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection

          -  Is sero-positive for Hepatitis C Virus (HCV), or has a history of delta virus
             hepatitis

          -  Has hypertension: blood pressure &gt; 170/100 mmHg

          -  History of cardiac rhythm disturbances

          -  Family history of congenital long QT syndrome, Brugada syndrome or unexplained sudden
             cardiac death

          -  Symptomatic heart failure, unstable angina, myocardial infarction, severe
             cardiovascular disease within 6 months prior to study entry

          -  History of malignancy, except for adequately treated basal cell carcinoma, squamous
             cell skin cancer, superficial bladder tumors, or in situ cervical cancer

          -  Has had major surgery within 1 month of screening

          -  Regular use of alcohol within 6 months prior to screening (ie, more than 14 units of
             alcohol per week)

          -  Evidence of severe systemic acute inflammation, sepsis, or hemolysis.

          -  Diagnosed with a significant psychiatric disorder.

          -  Use of recreational drugs such as cocaine, phencyclidine (PCP), and methamphetamines,
             within 1 year prior to the screening.

          -  History of allergy to bee sting

          -  Clinically significant history of any liver or kidney disease

          -  Presence of cholangitis, cholecystitis, cholestasis, or duct obstruction

          -  Clinically significant history or presence of poorly controlled/uncontrolled systemic
             disease

          -  History of fever within 2 weeks of screening

          -  Presence of any medical or psychiatric condition or social situation that impacts
             compliance or results in additional safety risk

          -  History of coagulopathy/stroke within past 6 months, and/or concurrent anticoagulant
             medication(s)
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <phone>626-304-3400</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 30, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 14, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Entecavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
