<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="75">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00412750</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLDT600A2406</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00412750</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00376389</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Telbivudine in Treatment naïve Patients With Hepatitis B e Antigen (HBeAg)-Positive Chronic Hepatitis B (CHB)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-label, Controlled, Multi-center Two-year Study Comparing Efficacy and Safety of Telbivudine, 600 mg PO in Combination With Peginterferon Alpha-2a sq 180 µg With Peginterferon Alpha-2a Monotherapy, and With Telbivudine Monotherapy in Treatment naïve Patients With HBeAg-positive CHB.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>Australia: Department of Health and Ageing Therapeutic Goods Administration</authority>
    <authority>Belgium: The Federal Public Service (FPS) Health, Food Chain Safety and Environment</authority>
    <authority>France: Afssaps - Agence française de sécurité sanitaire des produits de santé (Saint-Denis)</authority>
    <authority>Germany: Federal Institute for Drugs and Medical Devices</authority>
    <authority>Italy: Ministry of Health</authority>
    <authority>Netherlands: Medicines Evaluation Board (MEB)</authority>
    <authority>Spain: Ministry of Health and Consumption</authority>
    <authority>Switzerland: Federal Office of Public Health</authority>
    <authority>United Kingdom: Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency</authority>
    <authority>Israel: Ministry of Health</authority>
    <authority>Argentina: Administracion Nacional de Medicamentos, Alimentos y Tecnologia Medica</authority>
    <authority>Taiwan: National Bureau of Controlled Drugs</authority>
    <authority>Singapore: Health Sciences Authority</authority>
    <authority>New Zealand: Health and Disability Ethics Committees</authority>
    <authority>Hong Kong: Department of Health</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the combination of telbivudine 600 mg orally (PO) once daily and peginterferon
      alpha-2a 180 ug subcutaneous (sq) injection weekly for antiviral efficacy in comparison to
      peginterferon alpha-2a monotherapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Enrollment stopped for safety issues
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>December 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved HBV DNA Non-detectability With Peginterferon Alpha-2a Plus Telbivudine Combination Therapy Versus Peginterferon Alpha-2a Monotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At week 52</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The original primary efficacy variable was the percentage of patients achieving HBV DNA non-detectability utilizing polymerase chain reaction (PCR) (threshold for detection 300 copies/mL); however, this analysis was not performed due to premature study termination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With HBV DNA Non-detectability and Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) Normalization at Week 12 and Week 24 in Participants With HBeAg-positive Chronic Hepatitis B (CHB)</measure>
    <time_frame>Weeks 12 and 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The percentage of participants who achieved HBV DNA non-detectability using the COBAS Amplicor HBV Monitor assay utilizing polymerase chain reaction (PCR) (threshold for detection 300 copies/mL) and Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) normalization defined as ALT within normal limits on two successive visits for a patient with an elevated ALT (&gt;1.0 x upper limit normal) at baseline summarized at Weeks 12 and 24.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in HBV DNA Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Weeks 12 and 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The change from baseline in HBV DNA concentration at Weeks 12 and 24 was analyzed using an analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) model with baseline HBV DNA concentration (log10 copies/ml) as a covariate, treatment and country as factors.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Experienced Virologic Breakthrough at Weeks 48 and 52</measure>
    <time_frame>Weeks 48 and 52</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The percentage of participants with Virologic breakthrough at Week 48 and 52 by treatment. For the subgroup of patients on treatment who achieve HBV DNA &gt;= 1 log10 copies/mL reduction from baseline on 2 consecutive visits, Virologic Breakthrough is defined as HBV DNA &gt;= 1 log10 copies/mL from nadir on two consecutive visits.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Hepatitis B 'e' Antigen (HBeAg) Loss and HBeAg Seroconversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Weeks 18, 24, 48, 52 and Treatment completion (TC)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>HBeAg loss is defined as the loss of detectable serum HBeAg in a patient who was HBeAg positive at baseline. HBeAg seroconversion is defined as HBeAg loss with detectable Hepatitis B 'e' antibody (HBeAb). The efficacy was assessed for 18 weeks, 24 weeks, 48 weeks, 52 weeks and on treatment completion (TC).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved HBV DNA Non-detectability With Telbivudine Monotherapy Versus Peginterferon Alpha-2a Monotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 52</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Antiviral efficacy was assessed by percentage of patients achieving HBV DNA non-detectability assay utilizing polymerase chain reaction (PCR) (threshold for detection 300 copies/mL); however, this analysis was not performed due to premature study termination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved HBV DNA Non-detectability With Peginterferon Alpha-2a Plus Telbivudine Combination Therapy Versus Telbivudine Monotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 52</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Antiviral efficacy was assessed by percentage of patients achieving HBV DNA non-detectability assay utilizing polymerase chain reaction (PCR) (threshold for detection 300 copies/mL); however, this analysis was not performed due to premature study termination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">159</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis B</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LdT+ PEG-INF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Telbivudine (LdT) 600 mg orally once a day for 104 weeks in combination with peginterferon alpha-2a (PEG-INF)180 μg subcutaneous injection once a week for 52 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LdT Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Telbivudine (LdT) monotherapy: 600 mg orally once daily for 104 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-INF Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Peginterferon alpha-2a (PEG- INF) monotherapy: 180 μg subcutaneous injection once a week for 52 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telbivudine (LdT)</intervention_name>
    <description>600 mg orally once daily for 104 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>LdT+ PEG-INF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>LdT Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sebivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>peginterferon alpha-2a</intervention_name>
    <description>180 μg subcutaneous injection once a week for 52 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>LdT+ PEG-INF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-INF Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pegasys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Documented Chronic hepatitis B (CHB) defined by all of the following:

          -  Clinical history compatible with CHB

          -  Detectable serum Hepatitis B Surface Antigen (HBsAg) at the Screening visit and at
             least 6 months prior

          -  HBeAg-positive at the Screening visit

          -  Hepatitis B 'e' Antibody (HBeAb)-negative at the Screening visit

          -  History of evidence of chronic liver inflammation,

          -  Elevated serum Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) level (1.3 - 10 x upper limit of normal
             (ULN)) at the Screening visit

          -  Serum HBV DNA level ≥ 6 log10 copies/mL,

          -  Chronic liver inflammation on previous liver biopsy within the previous 24 months.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Co-infection with Hepatitis C Virus (HCV), Hepatitis D Virus (HDV), or Human
             Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV).

          -  Has any of the following drug therapy:

               -  Previously been treated in a trial with telbivudine

               -  Received nucleoside or nucleotide therapy whether approved or investigational

               -  Received any immunomodulatory treatment in the 12 months before Screening for
                  this study.

               -  Has a medical condition that required prolonged or frequent use of systemic
                  acyclovir or famciclovir.

               -  Has a medical condition that requires frequent or prolonged use of systemic
                  corticosteroids although inhaled or intra-articular corticosteroids are allowed.

               -  Has a medical condition requiring the chronic or prolonged use of potentially
                  hepatotoxic drugs or nephrotoxic drugs.

               -  Is currently abusing alcohol or illicit drugs or has a history of alcohol abuse
                  illicit substance abuse within the preceding two years.

               -  Uses other investigational drugs at the time of enrollment, or within 30 days or
                  5 half-lives of enrollment, whichever is longer.

               -  Is currently receiving methadone.

          -  Patient has any of the following:

               -  History of or clinical signs/symptoms of hepatic decompensation such as ascites,
                  esophageal variceal bleeding, hepatic encephalopathy, or spontaneous bacterial
                  peritonitis.

               -  History of malignancy of any organ system, treated or untreated, within the past
                  5 years whether or not there is evidence of local recurrence or metastases, with
                  the exception of localized basal cell carcinoma of the skin. Patients with
                  previous findings suggestive of possible HCC should have the disease ruled out
                  prior to entrance into the study.

               -  One or more additional known primary or secondary causes of liver disease other
                  than hepatitis B, including steatohepatitis.

               -  History of clinical and laboratory evidence of chronic pancreatitis, or
                  demonstrates a clinical and laboratory course consistent with current
                  pancreatitis.

          -  Has laboratory values during screening visit not within normal limits.

          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding.

          -  Is a women of child-bearing potential that is unwilling to practice birth control.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2011</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 14, 2011</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 15, 2006</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>December 2, 2010</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>novartis</name_title>
    <organization>novatis</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hepatitis B</keyword>
  <keyword>hepatitis B Virus (HBV)</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic hepatitis B</keyword>
  <keyword>telbivudine</keyword>
  <keyword>peginterferon</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Telbivudine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
