<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="193">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00446134</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RNA003142-204</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00446134</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Taribavirin Phase 2 Dose Finding Study for the Treatment of Hepatitis C Virus (HCV)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 2 Comparison of Weight-based Doses of Taribavirin Combined With Peginterferon Alfa-2b Versus Ribavirin Combined With Peginterferon Alfa-2b in Therapy-naïve Patients With Chronic Hepatitis C Virus Genotype 1 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Valeant Pharmaceuticals International, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Valeant Pharmaceuticals International, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the study is to select an optimal dose of taribavirin by comparing the
      efficacy and safety of 3 taribavirin dose levels, 20, 25, and 30 mg/kg/day, versus ribavirin
      800 to 1400 mg/day based on body weight, both administered in combination with peginterferon
      alfa-2b to therapy-naive patients with chronic Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) genotype 1 infection.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the study is to select an optimal dose of taribavirin by comparing the
      efficacy and safety of 3 taribavirin dose levels, 20, 25, and 30 mg/kg/day, versus ribavirin
      800 mg/day to 1400 mg/day based on subject body weight, with both drugs administered in
      combination with peginterferon alfa-2b to therapy-naive patients with chronic Hepatitis C
      Virus genotype 1 infection.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients With Either Undetectable Serum HCV RNA (&lt;100 Copies/ml) or at Least a 2-log Decrease From Baseline in Serum Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) at Treatment Week 12.</measure>
    <time_frame>Treatment Week 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The primary efficacy endpoint was the numbers of responders at Treatment Week (TW) 12. Responders are defined as patients achieving either viral negativity or a partial response (PR). Viral negativity is defined as &lt;100 copies/mL serum HCV RNA. A PR is defined as &lt; 100 copies/mL serum HCV RNA and at least a 2-log decrease from baseline in serum HCV RNA levels. Responder rates with corresponding 95% confidence intervals were estimated for each treatment group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients With Anemia (Hemoglobin &lt;10 g/dL) Up to Follow-up Week 24</measure>
    <time_frame>Treatment Week Follow-Up 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The primary safety endpoint will be the numbers of patients with hemoglobin &lt;10 g/dL (anemia) at any time during the treatment period. The comparison of anemia rates between taribavirin and ribavirin groups will be carried out using the Fisher's exact test or Chi-square test. The 95% confidence interval of the difference in proportion will be analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients With Undetected Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) (&lt;100 Copies/mL) at Treatment Week Follow-Up 24</measure>
    <time_frame>Treatment Week Follow-Up 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relapsers at Follow-Up Visit 24</measure>
    <time_frame>Follow-Up Week 24</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Includes patients who had undetectable Hepatitis Virus C (HVC) Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) at their last visit on drug.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">278</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral taribavirin tablet 20 mg/kg/day (Actual doses were 20-24 mg/kg/day) BID plus weekly subcutaneous injections of peginterferon alfa-2b (1.5 ug/kg/wk)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral taribavirin tablet 25 mg/kg/day (Actual doses were 25-29 mg/kg/day) BID plus weekly subcutaneous injections of peginterferon alfa-2b (1.5 ug/kg/wk)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral taribavirin 30 mg/kg/day (Actual doses were 30-34 mg/kg/day) BID plus weekly subcutaneous injections of peginterferon alfa-2b (1.5 ug/kg/wk)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral ribavirin 800 mg/day (body weight &lt;65 kg), 1000 mg/day (body weight 65-84 kg), 1200 mg/day (body weight 85-104 kg) or 1400 mg/day (body weight greater than or equal to 105 kg) BID plus weekly subcutaneous injections of peginterferon alfa-2b (1.5 ug/kg/wk)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Taribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral (200 mg) Tablet: 20mg/kg/day BID, patients will be treated for a total of 48 weeks. in addition, all patients will receive peginterferon alfa-2b (PEG-Intron) by weekly subcutaneous injection. Patients who complete treatment with study drug or discontinue treatment prematurely will enter a 24-week follow-up period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Viramidine</other_name>
    <other_name>RNA003142-204</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Taribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral (200 mg) Tablet: 25mg/kg/day BID, patients will be treated for a total of 48 weeks. in addition, all patients will receive peginterferon alfa-2b (PEG-Intron) by weekly subcutaneous injection. Patients who complete treatment with study drug or discontinue treatment prematurely will enter a 24-week follow-up period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Viramidine</other_name>
    <other_name>RNA003142-204</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Taribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral (200mg)Tablet: 30mg/kg/day BID, patients will be treated for a total of 48 weeks. in addition, all patients will receive peginterferon alfa-2b (PEG-Intron) by weekly subcutaneous injection. Patients who complete treatment with study drug or discontinue treatment prematurely will enter a 24-week follow-up period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Viramidine</other_name>
    <other_name>RNA003142-204</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral (200mg)Tablet: 800 mg/day, 1000 mg/day, 1200 mg/day, or 1400 mg/day BID, patients will be treated for a total of 48 weeks. in addition, all patients will receive peginterferon alfa-2b (PEG-Intron) by weekly subcutaneous injection. Patients who complete treatment with study drug or discontinue treatment prematurely will enter a 24-week follow-up period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4: Drug</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rebetol</other_name>
    <other_name>Copegus</other_name>
    <other_name>Ribasphere</other_name>
    <other_name>Virazole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Subject Inclusion Criteria

        To be eligible for enrollment, patients must meet all of the following criteria:

          1. At least 18 years of age

          2. Diagnosed with compensated chronic HCV genotype 1 infection that has not been treated
             with interferon, peginterferon, ribavirin or any experimental therapy for &gt;28 days

        2a Serum HCV RNA &gt;2000 copies/mL (780 IU/mL) 2b Liver biopsy performed within 3 years
        prior to screening consistent with chronic HCV infection 2c Criteria for compensated HCV
        infection, including normal prothrombin time, serum albumin and bilirubin levels (unless
        due to non-hepatitis factors) and no history or evidence of bleeding esophageal varices,
        ascites, or hepatic encephalopathy

        3 History of alanine aminotransferase (ALT) elevation either within 6 months prior to
        screening, at screening, or on retest 2 weeks after a negative screening test, or
        histologic evidence of HCV infection and a detectable viral load

        4 Platelet count ≥90,000/mm3

        5 Absolute neutrophil count ≥1200/mm3

        6 Hemoglobin ≥12.0 g/dL for females or ≥13.0 g/dL for males

        7 Antinuclear antibody (ANA) titer ≤1:320

        8 Serum creatinine &lt;1.5 mg/dL

        9 HbA1c ≤8.5% for diabetic patients

        10 Normal or adequately controlled TSH on prescription medication

        11 Alpha fetoprotein (AFP) &lt;20 ng/mL or hepatocellular carcinoma ruled out (ultrasound, CT
        or MRI scan) within 6 months prior to the study (Patients with an AFP &gt;20 ng/mL must have
        ongoing hepatocellular carcinoma screening during study as part of the patient's routine
        medical care)

        12 All other clinical laboratory values within normal limits, unless judged not clinically
        significant by the investigator

        13 Sterile or infertile (defined as vasectomy, tubal ligation, postmenopausal, or
        hysterectomy), or willing to use an approved method of double-barrier contraception
        (hormonal plus barrier or barrier plus barrier, eg, diaphragm plus condom) from the time
        of first dose administration until 6 months after the last dose

        14 Capable of understanding instructions, adhering to study schedules and requirements,
        and willing to provided informed consent

        Subject Exclusion Criteria

        Patients who have any of the following during the screening or Day 1 visit are not
        eligible for enrollment in this study:

          1. Positive HIV or HbsAg serology

          2. Severe psychiatric or neuropsychiatric disorders including severe depression, history
             of suicidal ideations or suicide attempt(s). (This would include patients with a
             history of suicidal ideations or suicide attempt(s) that occurred when the patient
             was a minor or many years ago; if the event occurred while under the influence of
             alcohol or drugs; if the suicidal ideations or suicide attempt(s) were connected to a
             traumatic event; if the patient was not hospitalized or treated; if the patient has
             obtained psychiatric clearance for treatment)

          3. History or clinical manifestations of significant metabolic, hematological,
             pulmonary, ischemic or unstable heart disease, gastrointestinal, neurological, renal,
             urological, endocrine, ophthalmologic (including severe retinopathy), or immune
             mediated disease

          4. History of thalassemia or other hemoglobinopathies (even if the hemoglobin is normal)

          5. Chronic hepatic disease other than hepatitis C

          6. Organ or bone marrow transplant

          7. Chronic (greater than 30 days) use of immunosuppressive medications including
             steroids in doses equivalent to 10 mg of prednisone or higher, 30 days prior to and
             anytime during the course of the study

          8. Female patients who are breast-feeding or have a positive pregnancy test at any time
             during the study

          9. Males whose female partners are pregnant

         10. Patients who have had a malignancy diagnosed and/or treated within the past 5 years,
             except for localized squamous or basal cell cancers treated by local excision

         11. Patients who have participated in a clinical trial and have received an
             investigational drug within 30 days prior to screening

         12. History of alcoholism or drug addiction 1 year prior to screening

         13. The use of methadone, buprenorphine or any similar drug, regardless of the prescribed
             indication or the length of time the patient has been on the drug

         14. Chronic (&gt;4 weeks duration) diarrhea, including irritable bowel disease

         15. Fibrosis score F4 (cirrhosis) based on Metavir or equivalent index

         16. Weight &gt;128 kg or &lt;40 kg

         17. Patients infected with mixed HCV genotypes
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fred Poordad, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center, 8635 W. 3rd Street, Suite 590W</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Poordad F, Lawitz E, Pozza R, et al. Efficacy and safety of weight-based regimens of taribavirin or ribavirin, given with peginterferon alfa-2b, 12 weeks after treatment (SVR12) in naive patients with genotype 1 hepatitis C. J Hepatol. 2009;50 Suppl 1:S8</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Poordad F, Lawitz E, Chun E, Hammond J. Treatment week 12 results of weight-based taribavirin versus weight-based ribavirin, both with peginterferon alfa-2b, in naive chronic hepatitis C, genotype 1 patients. J Hepatol. 2008;48 Suppl 2:S373</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lawitz E, Muir A, Poordad F, et al. Treatment week 24 results of weight-based taribavirin versus weight-based ribavirin, both with peginterfon alfa-2b, in naive chronic hepatitis C, genotype 1 patients. Hepatology. 2008;48 Suppl 1:433A</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Poordad F, Lawitz E, Hassanein T, et al. Sustained virologic response results for weight-based taribavirin versus weight-based ribavirin, in naive chronic hepatitis C, genotype 1 patients. Hepatology. 2009;50 Suppl 1:334A</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 20, 2012</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 8, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>September 20, 2011</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phase 2b Dose-Ranging Study</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
