<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="117">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02605304</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ACTG A5348</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1AI068636</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02605304</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>12 Weeks of Ledipasvir (LDV)/Sofosbuvir (SOF) With Weight-based Ribavirin vs. 24 Weeks of LDV/SOF</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Retreatment Strategies for Difficult-to-Treat Hepatitis C Virus (HCV)-Infected Individuals Who Have Failed Prior Direct Acting Antiviral (DAA)-Based Regimens</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AIDS Clinical Trials Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AIDS Clinical Trials Group</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Federal Government</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      People who are infected with Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) have a great chance of being cured of
      the infection when they are treated with sofosbuvir. However, in some instances, treatment
      with sofosbuvir-containing therapy does not work. It is not known if treating people with
      sofosbuvir again (retreatment) after it did not work the first time will work. There is an
      important need to understand retreatment options in those instances. This study is being
      done to see if two different regimens, ledipasvir with sofosbuvir and ribavirin for 12 weeks
      (Group A) and ledipasvir with sofosbuvir for 24 weeks (Group B) are well tolerated in
      HCV-infected persons where previous treatment with sofosbuvir failed. This study will also
      look at the safety of each regimen and how well the combination treatment of
      ledipasvir/sofosbuvir works in people who have cirrhosis (scarring of the liver) or HIV.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There is a pressing need to understand appropriate retreatment options for HCV-infected
      patients who fail direct acting antiviral (DAA)-based regimens. To date, over 100,000
      prescriptions have been written for SOF. Recent data indicate that the SOF-based treatment
      defined as SOF/RBV, SOF/pegylated-interferon (PEG)/RBV or SOF/simeprevir (SIM) +/- RBV have
      led to SVR4 in 70-92% of HCV genotype (GT) 1 patients, depending on the regimen used and
      presence of cirrhosis. Thus, there are a growing number of individuals who have failed
      SOF-based regimens and are in need of a retreatment strategy, the majority of which are
      anticipated to be HCV GT1, given the US distribution of genotypes. There are no data to
      inform retreatment strategies for HIV-infected individuals with SOF failure, who have
      traditionally represented a harder to treat group and are impacted by DAA-ARV interactions.

      This study is a phase II retreatment study of HCV GT1 HIV coinfected patients who have
      previous virologic failure on a SOF-based regimen. SOF-failures represent a challenging
      group to retreat as they have already failed one potent regimen, and in many cases may have
      failed prior regimens as well. This study will provide much needed pilot data evaluating
      retreatment strategies of LDV/SOF for prior SOF-failures in HIV/HCV coinfection, including
      those with cirrhosis.

      Participants in the study will be randomized to one of two treatment groups: 12 weeks of
      LDV/SOF with weight-based RBV or 24 weeks of LDV/SOF alone. The participants will be
      followed for an additional 24 weeks after completion of study treatment. The first 15
      participants on ARV regimens with a HIV PI/r with tenofovir will be required to participate
      in the PK component in order to participate in the study. These first 15 participants on
      PI/r with tenofovir who enroll to the study will undergo semi-intensive PK sampling
      (pre-dose, hour 1 and hour 4) at weeks 0 and 4 for quantification of tenofovir in plasma.
      After the first 15 participants have enrolled, subsequent participants taking HIV PI/r with
      tenofovir may opt out of the PK evaluations but still participate in the study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained virologic response 12 weeks after HCV antiviral therapy (SVR12)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of Grade 3 or higher AE, serious AE (SAE), or AE reported as the reason for permanent discontinuation of study treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From study treatment initiation to 30 days after study treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Renal toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>From study entry to study completion (Week 36 in Arm A, Week 48 in Arm B)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained Virologic Response at 4 weeks after treatment discontinuation (SVR4)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained Virologic Response at 24 weeks after treatment discontinuation (SVR24)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 24 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HCV RNA &lt;LLOQ (lower limit of quantification)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1, 2, 4, 8, 12 (and 16, 20, 24 in Arm B) weeks of treatment, and at 4, 12 and 24 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HIV-1 RNA &gt; 50 copies/mL</measure>
    <time_frame>Entry; at 4, 12 (and 24 in Arm B) weeks of treatment, and at 4 weeks after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV-1 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: LDV/SOP + RBV (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment followed by 24 weeks post-treatment follow-up</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: LDV/SOF (24 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment followed by 24 weeks post-treatment follow-up</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ledipasvir/sofosbuvir</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive one fixed dose tablet of LDV 90 mg/SOF 400 mg orally per day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: LDV/SOP + RBV (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: LDV/SOF (24 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>LDV/SOF</other_name>
    <other_name>Harvoni</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Based on weight at entry- For weight &lt;75 kg, participants will receive one 1000 mg tablet orally per day. For weight &gt;75 kg: participants will receive one 1200mg tablet orally per day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: LDV/SOP + RBV (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>RBV</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Provide written and informed consent

          -  Documentation of non-cirrhotic or cirrhotic status

          -  HIV-1 infection

          -  HCV GT-1 within 12 months prior to study entry

          -  Prior virologic treatment failure with SOF-containing regimen (SOF/RBV, SOF/PEG/RBV,
             and SOF/SIM).

          -  Body mass index (BMI) ≥ 18 kg/m2 within 42 days prior to study entry

          -  Certain laboratory values obtained within 42 days prior to study entry

          -  Hemoglobin ≥ 12.0 g/dL for male, ≥11.0 g/dL for female participants

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (SGOT) and Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (SGOT) &lt;
             10 x ULN

          -  Willing and able to provide written informed consent

          -  Female participants of reproductive potential must have a negative serum pregnancy
             test with a sensitivity of at least 25 mIU/mL performed at screening and within 48
             hours prior to study entry.

          -  Agreement to use at least two reliable forms of contraceptive simultaneously for
             duration of study and for 6 months afterward

          -  Compliance with the dosing instructions and study schedule of assessments

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Receipt of any investigational drug or device within 60 days prior to study entry

          -  Prior exposure to a DAA other than SOF and SIM

          -  Chronic liver disease of a non-HCV etiology

          -  Presence of active or acute AIDS-defining opportunistic infections within 42 days
             prior to study entry

          -  Active, serious infection (other than HIV-1 or HCV) requiring parenteral antibiotics,
             antivirals, or antifungals within 42 days prior to study entry

          -  Hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection (defined as HBsAg positive) within 42 days prior to
             study entry

          -  History of clinically significant hemoglobinopathy

          -  Chronic current use of systemically administered immunosuppressive agents

          -  History of solid organ transplantation

          -  Current or prior history of clinical hepatic decompensation

          -  History of a gastrointestinal disorder (or postoperative condition) that could
             interfere with the absorption of the study drug

          -  History of significant or symptomatic pulmonary disease, cardiac disease, or
             porphyria that in the opinion of the investigator would interfere with the study

          -  History of difficulty with blood collection and/or poor venous access for the
             purposes of phlebotomy

          -  Active drug or alcohol use or dependence

          -  Use of any prohibited concomitant medications per the LDV/SOF product labeling,
             within 42 days prior to study entry

          -  Known hypersensitivity to RBV, SOF, LDV, their metabolites, or formulation excipients
             or any other contraindication to the use of RBV, SOF or LDV

          -  Currently receiving zidovudine (ZDV), didanosine (ddI), stavudine (d4T) or tipranavir

          -  Acute HIV infection defined as the phase immediately following infection during which
             anti-HIV antibodies are undetectable

          -  Known hepatocellular carcinoma.

          -  Breastfeeding or pregnancy

          -  A male participant with a pregnant female partner

          -  Receipt of colony stimulating agents, including but not limited to erythropoietin,
             within 42 days prior to study entry
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Annie Luetkemeyer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco HIV/AIDS CRS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer J. Kiser, PharmD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Colorado, Denver</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 12, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 12, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
