<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01392170</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2011-0184</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2011-01465</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01392170</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pegasys in Patients With Chronic Myeloid Leukemia (CML)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Pegylated Ifná-2a (Pegasys) in Patients With Chronic Myeloid Leukemia Who Have Minimal Residual Disease While Receiving Therapy With Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical research study is to learn if adding pegylated interferon-alfa 2a
      (Pegasys) to the TKI that you are already receiving can help to control CML. The safety of
      this treatment combination will also be studied.

      Pegasys is a form of the drug interferon. It is designed to help the body's immune system to
      fight infections. It may also affect the body's response to cancer.

      A TKI (imatinib mesylate, nilotinib, or dasatinib) is designed to bind to and shut off a
      protein in tumor cells called Bcr-Abl. Shutting Bcr-Abl off may prevent CML cells from
      growing, and may cause them to die.

      You are already receiving a TKI. This consent form will describe the administration of
      Pegasys, any tests and procedures that need to be performed while you are receiving Pegasys,
      and any risks/benefits there may be from receiving Pegasys.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Drug Administration:

      If you are found to be eligible to take part in this study, you will receive Pegasys through
      a needle under the skin 1 time each week while you are on study. You will be taught how to
      use the study drug at the first visit and will administer it to yourself at all future
      doses.

      You will continue receiving the TKI you are already taking at the dose and frequency you
      have been receiving it when you began taking part in this study.

      Study Visits:

      At every study visit, you will be asked about any side effects you may have had and to list
      any drugs you may be taking.

      Every 1-2 weeks for 8 weeks, then every 6-8 weeks after that, blood (about 1-2 teaspoons)
      will be drawn for routine tests.

      Every 3 months for 6 months, then every 6-12 months after that, you will have a complete
      physical exam, including measurement of your vital signs.

      Every 3-6 months for 1 year, you will have a bone marrow aspirate to check the status of the
      disease and to check for changes in your chromosomes.

      Every 3-6 months for 1 year, then every 6-12 months after that, blood (about 1 teaspoon)
      will be drawn to check the levels of leukemia in the blood.

      Length of Study:

      You may continue taking Pegasys for as long as the doctor thinks it is in your best
      interest. You will no longer be able to take the study drug if the disease gets worse, if
      intolerable side effects occur, or if you are unable to follow study directions.

      This is an investigational study. Pegasys is FDA approved and commercially available for the
      treatment of CML. TKIs (imatinib, nilotinib, and dasatinib) are FDA approved and
      commercially available for the treatment of CML. The combination of these drugs to treat CML
      is investigational.

      Up to 50 patients will take part in this study. All will be enrolled at MD Anderson.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Slow Accrual
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>October 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Achieved of Major Molecular Response (MMR) or Complete Molecular Response (CMR)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from start of treatment with PEG-IFNá-2a</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Molecular response defined as: major molecular response (MMR) corresponds to a BCR-ABL1/ABL1 ratio of &lt;=0.01. Complete molecular response (CMR) is defined as undetectable BCR-ABL1 transcripts. Molecular response measured every 3 months (a total of 4 assessments within one year of therapy).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Leukemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-IFNá-2a</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PEG-IFNá-2a (Pegasys) 45 mcg subcutaneously as single weekly dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PEG-IFNá-2a</intervention_name>
    <description>45 mcg given subcutaneously as a single weekly dose for 24 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PEG-IFNá-2a</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pegasys</other_name>
    <other_name>Peginterferon Alpha-2a</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients 16 years or older with Philadelphia chromosome (Ph)-positive or
             BCR-ABL1-positive CML (as determined by cytogenetics, FISH, or PCR).

          2. Patients are receiving an FDA-approved TKI for the management of CML.

          3. Patients must have received TKI therapy for at least 24 months and not have increased
             their TKI dose in the last 6 months.

          4. Patients must be in complete cytogenetic remission.

          5. Patients must have detectable BCR-ABL1 transcript levels meeting at least one of the
             following criteria: 1. The patient has received therapy for at least 2 years and does
             not have a sustained major molecular response, or 2. The patient has received therapy
             for at least 5 years and does not have a sustained complete molecular response.

          6. Patients must not have had a known continuous interruption of TKI therapy of greater
             than 14 consecutive days or for a total of 6 weeks in the 6 months prior to
             enrollment.

          7. Patients must sign an informed consent indicating that they are aware of the
             investigational nature of this study.

          8. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status &lt;/= 2.

          9. Adequate organ function defined as: bilirubin &lt; 2x upper limit of normal (ULN)
             (unless associated with Gilbert's syndrome), creatinine &lt;/= 1.5x ULN, and serum
             glutamate pyruvate transaminase (sGPT) or serum glutamate oxaloacetate transaminase
             (sGOT) &lt;/= 2.5x ULN.

         10. Men and women of childbearing potential should practice effective methods of
             contraception. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine
             pregnancy test within 1 week of enrollment.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients receiving any non-FDA approved TKI.

          2. Patients who are pregnant or breast-feeding.

          3. Patients with clinically significant heart disease (NYHA Class III or IV).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alfonso Quintas-Cardama, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 13, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 8, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>March 31, 2015</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Myeloid Leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>CML</keyword>
  <keyword>Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>TKI</keyword>
  <keyword>Complete cytogenetic remission</keyword>
  <keyword>CCyR</keyword>
  <keyword>Minimal residual disease</keyword>
  <keyword>MRD</keyword>
  <keyword>PEG-IFNa-2a</keyword>
  <keyword>Pegasys</keyword>
  <keyword>Peginterferon Alpha-2a</keyword>
  <keyword>Philadelphia chromosome (Ph)-positive</keyword>
  <keyword>BCR-ABL1-positive</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelogenous, Chronic, BCR-ABL Positive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm, Residual</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2a</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
