<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="671">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00496912</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RO1 DA016065-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00496912</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Management of Hepatitis C in HIV-Infected and Uninfected IDUs</brief_title>
  <official_title>Management of Hepatitis C in HIV-Infected and Uninfected IDUs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <authority>United States: Federal Government</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if hepatitis C has damaged the liver, whether each
      subject's hepatitis C is treatable with currently available medicines, whether patient
      education groups before treatment help more patients start hepatitis C treatment, and if
      hepatitis C treatment with peginterferon and ribavirin given either by directly observed
      therapy or standard of care can be successfully given to persons who use or have used
      injection drugs.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Injection drug use is the predominant mode of hepatitis C (HCV) transmission in the United
      States and most injection drug users (IDUs) have HCV infection. HCV infection can cause
      progressive hepatic fibrosis (cirrhosis) over 20 or more years, leading, in some patients,
      to end-stage liver disease, hepatocellular carcinoma and death. Coinfection with human
      immunodeficiency virus (HIV) is present in 20-30% of HCV-infected IDUs, and is associated
      with the more rapid progression of HCV-related liver disease causing HCV infection to be
      considered as an opportunistic infection. While treatment of hepatitis C with pegylated
      interferon alfa and ribavirin (PEG/RBV) eradicates HCV infection in approximately one-half
      of patients, persons receiving methadone maintenance therapy, those who have recently used
      illicit drugs, and those with comorbidities (e.g., HIV infection, psychiatric disease) have
      been largely excluded from HCV treatment protocols. This research addresses the reality that
      the persons most affected by HCV infection (IDUs) are the least studied and the least
      treated, a disparity that becomes even more compelling as the success of HCV therapy
      increases. The principal goal of this research proposal is to expand the proportion of
      former and active injection drug users (IDUs) with HIV co-infection that benefit from
      hepatitis C care by assessing eligibility for treatment, medical necessity, and
      effectiveness of enhanced patient education prior to the initiation of HCV treatment among
      this patient population. To achieve these objectives, we plan to ask three fundamental
      questions: (1) what proportion of IDUs are eligible for hepatitis C virus (HCV) therapy
      based on both established and controversial criteria; (2) what proportion of IDUs currently
      need HCV treatment according to 2002 NIH consensus guidelines; and (3) what proportion of
      these treatment-eligible IDUs will initiate HCV therapy provided at no cost either as
      directly observed therapy compared to standard of care and is HCV treatment of IDUs more
      effective when enhanced patient education is provided prior to the initiation of HCV
      treatment. By answering these questions, we will 1) characterize the extent to which these
      various criteria affect treatment eligibility among IDUs; 2) define the magnitude of the
      medical need for treatment in these settings; and 3) evaluate the effectiveness of directly
      observed therapy versus standard of care and patient education on the initiation of HCV
      treatment. Overall, the study will provide much needed data to guide development of policies
      and guidelines for the treatment of HCV infection among IDUs, the largest risk group in the
      United States.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1. The proportion of IDUs who have clear medical contraindications to HCV treatment. 2. The prevalence of significant hepatic fibrosis among treatment eligible IDUs. 3. The proportion of treatment-eligible IDUs who initiate PEG/RBV therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of IDUs without clear contraindications who might be excluded by each of the 7 controversial contraindications.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">410</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C Virus</condition>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Peginterferon/ribavirin</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peginterferon/Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>peginterferon, ribavirin, standard doses</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>no other names. These are standard names.</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Must use or have used injection drugs

          -  Must have a reactive HCV antibody

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Does not have an absolute contraindication to HCV treatment:

               -  HCV RNA not detected by PCR.

               -  Pregnant or not willing to use birth control.

               -  Life expectancy &lt; 2 years.

               -  Severe depression with suicidal ideation.

               -  Allergic reaction to PEG/RBV.

               -  Severe hematologic abnormality that is likely to be exacerbated by treatment.

               -  Renal insufficiency.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark S Sulkowski, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Seal KH, Currie SL, Shen H, Anand BS, Bini EJ, Brau N, Jeffers L, Wright TL; VA HCV-001 Study Group. Hepatitis C treatment candidacy and outcomes among 4318 US veterans with chronic hepatitis C virus infection: does a history of injection drug use matter? J Clin Gastroenterol. 2007 Feb;41(2):199-205.</citation>
    <PMID>17245220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grebely J, Conway B, Raffa JD, Lai C, Krajden M, Tyndall MW. Hepatitis C virus reinfection in injection drug users. Hepatology. 2006 Nov;44(5):1139-45.</citation>
    <PMID>17058216</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mehta SH, Lucas GM, Mirel LB, Torbenson M, Higgins Y, Moore RD, Thomas DL, Sulkowski MS. Limited effectiveness of antiviral treatment for hepatitis C in an urban HIV clinic. AIDS. 2006 Nov 28;20(18):2361-9.</citation>
    <PMID>17117023</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2009</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 17, 2009</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 5, 2007</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Jag H. Khalsa, Ph.D., Chief, Medical Consequences</name_title>
    <organization>NIDA</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hepatitis C virus</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>IV Drug users</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Naive</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Experienced</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
