<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="79">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00724373</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P05269</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00724373</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of HCV Genotype 1 Patients in the UK Treated With ViraferonPeg and Rebetol (Study P05269)(COMPLETED)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Retrospective Data Study of HCV Genotype 1 Patients in the UK Treated With ViraferonPeg and Rebetol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United Kingdom: Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed as a retrospective data review of medical records from participants
      selected from specialist secondary and tertiary care centers across the United Kingdom (UK),
      specializing in Hepatitis C treatment. The study is non-interventional and is designed to
      identify subgroups of Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) genotype 1 participants in the 'real world',
      including the relation between subgroup characteristics and treatment responsiveness.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Physicians will record information (from the time of first exposure to pegylated interferon
      alfa-2b and ribavirin) from the medical notes of participants who fit the inclusion
      criteria. To prevent selection bias, data are to be taken from the latest consecutive,
      unique participants seen by the physician over the previous 48 months. This provides a
      method of random sampling from a physician practice.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Cohort, Time Perspective: Retrospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participants With Treatment Success</measure>
    <time_frame>Data will be collected from the start of first exposure to pegylated interferon alfa-2b and ribavirin combination therapy. Participants who have successfully completed treatment will have data collected for a follow-up period of at least 24 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Identify subgroups of genotype 1 participants to better understand factors affecting response rates &amp; treatment outcomes &amp; to provide predictive models of refractory or responsive phenotypes to aid in HCV treatment, management, &amp; drug development. Treatment success is defined as those who had achieved sustained virological response (i.e. undetectable viraemia 24 weeks post therapy completion).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">442</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with genotype 1 Hepatitis C Virus infection.</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with genotype 1 Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) infection who have been treated with pegylated interferon alfa-2b and ribavirin in the preceding 48 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peginterferon alfa-2b (SCH 54031)</intervention_name>
    <description>Peginterferon alfa-2b plus ribavirin will be administered according to the products' labeling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with genotype 1 Hepatitis C Virus infection.</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PegIntron</other_name>
    <other_name>ViraferonPeg</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin (SCH 18908)</intervention_name>
    <description>Peginterferon alfa-2b plus ribavirin will be administered according to the products' labeling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with genotype 1 Hepatitis C Virus infection.</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rebetol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants with genotype 1 HCV infection who have been treated with pegylated interferon
        alfa-2b and ribavirin in the preceding 48 months at sites in the UK.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants with genotype 1 HCV infection who have been treated with pegylated
             interferon alfa-2b and ribavirin in the preceding 48 months will be included. They
             will be divided into:

          -  Completer participants: Patients with a diagnosis of HCV genotype 1 who have
             completed a course of interferon alfa-2b and ribavirin, with no prior treatment for
             HCV (ie, previously treatment naïve). Completer participants must have at least 24
             weeks of follow up data available post completion of treatment to ensure ability to
             assess SVR rates.

          -  Early terminators: Participants who have terminated treatment early due to adverse
             events or other reasons (ie, exposure is incomplete).

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants currently undergoing therapy and therefore have not terminated
             treatment, ie, exposure is still ongoing.

          -  Co-infected HCV participants (eg, human immunodeficiency virus [HIV] or hepatitis B
             virus [HBV]).

          -  Participants who received their first HCV treatment in relation to a clinical trial.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>September 24, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 25, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>May 6, 2010</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
