<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="53">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01496807</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCC-16755</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01496807</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Yervoy With Sylatron Unresectable Stage 3 or 4 Melanoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ib Study of Yervoy With Sylatron for Patients With Unresectable Stages IIIB/C/IV Melanoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to see how much of the drug Yervoy can be safely tolerated when
      it is given to people who are also receiving a drug called Sylatron. Investigators also wish
      to find out whether the addition of Yervoy increases the chance that Sylatron will cause a
      rise in the level of antibodies in the patient's blood that recognize their own tissues,
      known as &quot;autoimmune&quot; antibodies. Investigators also want to find out how likely it is that
      their tumor will shrink.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 Months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To assess the safety, toxicities and tolerability of a regimen of 3 mcg/kg weekly Sylatron with concurrent induction Yervoy at 3, then if well tolerated, at 10 mg/kg every three weeks four times, in participants with unresectable stages IIIC/IV melanoma, and to define a well tolerated dose of Yervoy in that combination, if any.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Induction of Autoimmune Antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>48 Months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>This study is not designed to statistically test the efficacy of treatment, and no inferential analyses will be performed.
Autoimmune antibody parameters will be listed and summarized using means, standard deviations, and percentage coefficients of variation. Investigators wish to look for evidence of serologic and clinical autoimmunity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Overall Response (OR)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 Months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall response by both immune-related response criteria (irRC) and Modified World Health Organization (mWHO) will also be assessed as a secondary endpoint.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">31</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants are randomized to Yervoy induction at 3 mg/kg every 3 weeks for four doses for 12 weeks, and all patients simultaneously receive Sylatron induction at 3 μg/kg/week) for 8 weeks, followed by Sylatron. Participants will receive Yervoy induction therapy for 12 weeks and Sylatron therapy for up to 156 weeks, or until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity or patient decision to discontinue.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants are randomized to Yervoy induction at 10 mg/kg every 3 weeks for four doses for 12 weeks, and all patients simultaneously receive Sylatron induction at 3 μg/kg/week) for 8 weeks, followed by Sylatron. Participants will receive Yervoy induction therapy for 12 weeks and Sylatron therapy for up to 156 weeks, or until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity or patient decision to discontinue.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sylatron</intervention_name>
    <description>Sylatron - Once per week for 12 weeks (while receiving Yervoy), given as an injection under the skin. Both groups will receive the SAME dose of Sylatron.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PEG-Intron</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Yervoy</intervention_name>
    <description>Yervoy - Once every 3 weeks for 12 weeks (4 times total), given over a 90-minute intravenous infusion (through the vein). The 2 groups will receive DIFFERENT doses of Yervoy as outlined below.
Group 1: Yervoy, 3 milligrams (mg) per kilogram (kg) of body weight, every 3 weeks for 12 weeks (4 times).
Group 2: Yervoy, 10 milligrams (mg) per kilogram (kg) of body weight, every 3 weeks for 12 weeks (4 times).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: Yervoy with Sylatron</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ipilimumab</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Must have cytologically or histologically-confirmed and unresectable melanoma,
             previously untreated systemically other than a BRAF inhibitor for metastatic disease,
             meeting one of the following American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) staging
             criteria: AJCC Stage IV (Tany,Nany,M1); AJCC Stage IIIB/C patients with unresectable
             nodal/locoregional involvement; Patients with cutaneous, ocular or mucosal melanoma
             are eligible

          -  Must have adequate hepatic, renal and bone marrow function as defined by the
             following parameters obtained within 4 weeks prior to initiation of study treatment.
             Hematologic Criteria: white blood count (WBC) &gt;/= 3.0 x 10^9/L, Platelet &gt; 100 x
             10^9/L, Hemoglobin &gt;/= 9 g/dL or 5.6 mmol/L; Renal and Hepatic Functional Criteria:
             Serum creatinine &lt; 2.0 mg/dL or &lt; 140 μmol/L, serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase
             (SGOT) and serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase (SGPT) &lt; 2 times upper normal limit of
             laboratory normal (ULN)

          -  Must have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1

          -  Must give informed consent according to institutional policy

          -  Must be willing to give written informed consent and must be able to adhere to dose
             and visit schedules

          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must be using a medically accepted method
             of birth control prior to Screening and agree to continue its use during the study or
             be surgically sterilized (eg, hysterectomy or tubal ligation). Females of
             childbearing potential should be counseled in the appropriate use of birth control
             while in this study. Females who are not currently sexually active must agree and
             consent to use one of the above-mentioned methods should they become sexually active
             while participating in the study.

          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test
             (beta-hCG) at Screening.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Female patients who are pregnant, intend to become pregnant, or are nursing

          -  Previously treated with interferon alpha 2b, Sylatron or Yervoy therapy for melanoma

          -  Patients whose disease can be completely surgically resected

          -  Have not recovered from the effects of recent surgery

          -  Patients with a history of prior malignancy within the past 2 years other than
             surgically cured squamous or basal cell carcinoma of the skin, or cervical carcinoma
             in situ

          -  Have severe cardiovascular disease, ie. arrhythmias requiring chronic treatment,
             congestive heart failure (NYHA Class III or IV) or symptomatic ischemic heart disease

          -  Patients with thyroid dysfunction not responsive to therapy

          -  Patients who, in the opinion of the investigator, have uncontrolled diabetes mellitus

          -  Suffering from an active autoimmune disease except medically controlled
             hypothyroidism and vitiligo

          -  An active and/or uncontrolled infection, including active hepatitis

          -  Have a history of seropositivity for HIV

          -  Pre-existing psychiatric condition, including but not limited to: History of severe
             depression (including Hospitalization for depression, Electroconvulsive therapy for
             depression, Depression that resulted in a prolonged absence from work and/or
             significant disruption of daily functions); Suicidal of homicidal ideation and/or
             suicidal or homicidal attempt; History of severe psychiatric disorders (eg,
             psychosis, post-traumatic stress disorder or mania); Past history or current use of
             lithium and/or antipsychotic drugs

          -  A clinical diagnosis of substance abuse of the one or more of the following drugs,
             within the following timeframes, (not including time spent in detoxification,
             hospitalization or incarceration): Alcohol, intravenous drug use (IVDU),
             inhalational, psychotropics, narcotics, cocaine, prescription or over-the-counter
             drugs: within 1 year of the Screening visit; Receiving methadone, buprenorphine
             hydrochloride (HCL), and/or butorphanol tartrate within 1 year of Screening visit,
             unless participant has drug screen negative for other (non-narcotic) drugs documented
             in past year and repeated negative within 2 months of Screening visit; Multi-drug
             abuse (2 or more substances in 17a and 17b) within 3 years of Screening visit; If the
             patient's historic marijuana use is deemed excessive by the principal investigator
             (PI), or medically qualified individual or is interfering with the patient's life,
             then the patient is not eligible and should not be screened. If patient's marijuana
             use is not deemed excessive by PI and does not interfere with life, the patient must
             be instructed to discontinue any current use of recreational marijuana prior to entry
             into study.

          -  Patients with a medical condition requiring chronic systemic corticosteroids

          -  Known to be allergic to the drug substance or any of the excipients in the Sylatron
             or Yervoy formulation

          -  Patients who are in a situation or have any condition that, in the opinion of the
             investigator, may interfere with optimal participation in the study

          -  Have used any investigational drugs within 30 days of study entry

          -  Are participating in any other clinical treatment study
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffrey Weber, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.moffitt.org/research--clinical-trials/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Moffitt Cancer Center Clinical Trials website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>October 8, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 19, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>unresectable</keyword>
  <keyword>stage 3</keyword>
  <keyword>stage 4</keyword>
  <keyword>autoimmune</keyword>
  <keyword>antibodies</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Peginterferon alfa-2b</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
