<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="19">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01499498</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BOC_PK</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01499498</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Boceprevir and Sildenafil Pharmacokinetics Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability and Pharmacokinetic Profile of Boceprevir and Sildenafil When Dosed Separately and Together in Healthy Male Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Imperial College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United Kingdom: Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a healthy volunteer study looking at the interactions between two drugs: boceprevir
      and sildenafil.

      New drugs are being developed to treat people with the chronic viral infection hepatitis C.
      Very little is know how these new treatments interact with other medications such as the
      drugs used to treat erectile dysfunction.

      The purpose of this study is to look at levels of both a new hepatitis C drug called
      boceprevir (BOC) and an existing erectile dysfunction drug called sildenafil to see if they
      affect the blood levels of each other when given separately and together.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Total duration for each participant will be up to 40 days plus a screening visit 1 - 3 weeks
      prior to the start of the study.

      They will visit the clinic on 10 occasions: screening visit, baseline visit (day 0), day 1,
      a visit between day 4 and 7, day 10, day 14, day 15, day 16, day 17 and a follow up visit
      between days 26 and 40.

      The total amount of blood collected from participants during the entire study will be no
      greater than 350 ml in total (around 23 tablespoons).

      At the screening visit a clinical assessment will be performed. At the baseline visit
      participants will attend the clinic fasted and will be required to remain on the unit for
      approximately 14 hours.

      On the morning of the visit clinical assessments will be performed. Sildenafil 25mg (1
      tablet) will be administered with a standardised meal. Blood samples will be taken at the
      following times in order to measure the levels of sildenafil in the blood: predose,0.5, 1,
      2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10,12 and 24 hours post dose.

      On day Day 10 boceprevir will be initiated 800mg (4 capsules 3 times a day) for the next 4
      days on day 14 the participants will attend the clinic for a witnessed dose of boceprevir
      and safety assessment.

      On day 15 the participants will attend for their 2nd long visit (10 hours) when they will be
      administered boceprevir (BOC) 800mg (4 capsules) with a standardised meal then have blood
      samples taken at the following times in order to measure the levels of BOC in the blood:
      predose,0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 and 8 hours post dose.

      After the 8 hour blood collection participants will be administered boceprevir (BOC) 800mg
      (4 capsules) with food and they will self administer BOC 800mg (4 capsules) with food at
      home 8 hours later.

      On day 16 participants will attend for the 3rd long visit (14 hours) where they will be
      administered boceprevir (BOC) 800mg (4 capsules) and sildenafil 25mg with a standardised
      meal. Blood samples will be taken at the following times in order to measure the levels of
      both BOC and sildenafil in the blood: predose,0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 and 8 hours post dose.

      After the 8 hour blood collection participants will be administered boceprevir (BOC) 800mg
      (4 capsules) with food and will then self administer BOC 800mg (4 capsules) with food at
      home 8 hours later. This will be their last dose of study medication. They will return the
      next day for a final blood test post 24 hours. A final visit between days 26 and 40 will be
      performed including clinical assessments.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Pharmacokinetics Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sildenafil Alone Maximum Plasma Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Single dose sildenafil 25mg will be administered with food. Intensive pharmacokinetic sampling will be taken over a 24 hour period (0, 0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 24 hours post dose)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Boceprevir Alone Maximum Plasma Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>day 10-15</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Day 10 commence BOC 800mg three times a day with food. On day 15 at steady state, subjects will attend for witnessed dosing and an intensive pharmacokinetic visit over 8 hours (samples drawn 0, 0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 and 8 hours post dose)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sildenafil Maximum Plasma Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 16</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>administer BOC 800mg and single dose sildenafil 25mg with food. Intensive pharmacokinetic sampling will be taken over a 24 hour period (0, 0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 24 hours post dose)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Boceprevir Maximum Plasma Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 16</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>administer BOC 800mg and single dose sildenafil 25mg with food. Intensive pharmacokinetic sampling will be taken over a 24 hour period (0, 0.5, 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 24 hours post dose)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Patients With Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - 16</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The number of repeated adverse events will be used to assess the safety of the drugs in combination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">13</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sildenafil and Boceprevir</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy volunteers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sildenafil and Boceprevir</intervention_name>
    <description>25mg once/800mg three times a day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sildenafil and Boceprevir</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Viagra and Victrelis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  The ability to understand and sign a written informed consent form, prior to
             participation in any screening procedures and must be willing to comply with all
             study requirements.

          -  Subjects in good health upon medical history, physical exam, and laboratory testing
             and BMI &lt;32.

          -  Subjects who are heterosexually active must use two forms of barrier contraception
             (e.g., condom with spermicide) during heterosexual intercourse, from screening
             through completion of the study including 10 days following last dose of study drug.

          -  Have no serologic evidence of HIV or HCV infection through antibody testing at
             screening.

          -  Have screening laboratory results (haematology, chemistry) that fall within the
             normal range of the central laboratory's reference ranges unless the results have
             been determined by the Investigator to have no clinical relevance

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any serious or active medical or psychiatric illness which, in the opinion of the
             Investigator, would interfere with subject treatment, assessment, or compliance with
             the protocol. This would include any active clinically significant renal, cardiac,
             hepatic, pulmonary, vascular, metabolic (thyroid disorders, adrenal disease),
             immunodeficiency disorders, active infection, or malignancy.

          -  Previous participation in an investigational trial involving administration of any
             investigational compound within 1 month prior to the study screening.

          -  Clinically relevant alcohol or drug use (positive drug screen) or history of alcohol
             or drug use considered by the Investigator to be sufficient to hinder compliance with
             treatment, follow-up procedures or evaluation of adverse events. Smoking is
             permitted, but tobacco intake should remain consistent throughout the study.

          -  Any medication taken listed in protocol including over-the-counter medications and
             herbal products within 21 days of commencing study drug dosing with the exception of
             vitamins and/or paracetamol. When a concomitant medication is necessary, this will be
             reviewed by the Investigator and if not contraindicated, may be continued at the same
             dose and frequency during the study period.

          -  History of drug sensitivity or drug allergy which in the opinion of the investigator
             may put the subject at increased risk of drug reactions during the study.

          -  Subjects with female partners who are pregnant will not be allowed to enter the study
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alan Winston, MBChB MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Imperial College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W2 1NY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 6, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 4, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>October 9, 2014</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthy volunteers</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sildenafil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
