<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="243">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on December 13, 2015</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00705224</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P05562</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00705224</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Insulin Resistance on the Safety and Efficacy of Pegylated Interferon and Ribavirin Treatment in HCV (Study P05562)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Observational Multicenter Study to Evaluate Influence of Insulin Resistance on the Safety and Efficacy (as Measured by Sustained Virological Response) of Treatment With Any Pegylated Interferon and Ribavirin (Standard of Care) in Different Populations of HCV Patients in Russia.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>Russia: Ethics Committee</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Na誰ve patients with chronic hepatitis C (CHC) of any genotype will be treated with a
      standard treatment regimen (pegylated interferon and ribavirin) according to routine
      clinical practice in Russia. The objective of this study is to examine the influence of
      insulin resistance on the safety and efficacy of treatment with pegylated interferon and
      ribavirin and to determine the prevalence of insulin resistance in different populations of
      CHC patients.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      consecutive patient sampling
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Cohort, Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved Sustained Virological Response as Assessed at End of Study</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks following completion of 24 or 48 weeks of therapy</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Sustained Virological response (SVR) was assessed at the end of the study (Visit 4) to investigate the presence or absence of SVR. SVR was defined as undetectable plasma hepatitis C virus RNA (HCV-RNA) at 24 weeks after termination of treatment. Visit 4 was considered Week 48 or Week 72 depending on a treatment duration of 24 or 48 weeks respectively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved Sustained Virological Response as Assessed at End of Study by HCV Genotype and Presence of Insulin-Resistance at Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks following completion of 24 or 48 weeks of therapy</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>SVR was assessed at the end of the study (Visit 4) by HCV genotype (I, II, III, or other) and presence of insulin-resistance at baseline (defined as Homeostasis model assessment - of insulin-resistance [HOMA-IR] &gt;3) to investigate the presence or absence of SVR. SVR was defined as undetectable plasma HCV-RNA at 24 weeks after termination of treatment. Visit 4 was considered Week 48 or Week 72 depending on a treatment duration of 24 or 48 weeks respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved Response Following Treatment as Assessed at End of Treatment by HCV Genotype and Presence of Insulin-Resistance at Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24 or 48 after treatment start</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Response following treatment (RFT) was assessed at the end of treatment (Visit 3) by HCV genotype (I, II, III, or other) and presence of insulin-resistance at baseline (defined as HOMA-IR &gt;3) to investigate the presence or absence of RFT. RFT was defined as undetectable plasma HCV-RNA at end of treatment. Visit 3 was considered Week 24 or Week 48 after treatment start depending on treatment duration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Demonstrated Virological Relapse as Assessed at End of Study by HCV Genotype and Presence of Insulin-Resistance at Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks following completion of 24 or 48 weeks of therapy</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Virological relapse (VR) was assessed at the end of the study (Visit 4) by HCV genotype (I, II, III, or other) and presence of insulin-resistance at baseline (defined as HOMA-IR &gt;3) to investigate the percentage of participants who demonstrated VR. VR was defined as undetectable plasma HCV-RNA (RFT +) at end of treatment (Visit 3- considered Week 24 or Week 48 after treatment start depending on treatment duration), but lost RFT (considered sustained non-Responders) at end of study (Visit 4- considered Week 48 or Week 72 depending on a treatment duration of 24 or 48 weeks respectively).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants Who Achieved Early Virological Response as Assessed at Visit 2 by HCV Genotype and Presence of Insulin-Resistance at Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 after treatment start</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Early Virological response (EVR) was assessed at 12 weeks after treatment start (Visit 2) by HCV genotype (I, II, III, or other) and presence of insulin-resistance at baseline (defined as HOMA-IR &gt;3) to investigate the percentage of participants who achieved EVR. EVR was defined as a substantial (greater than 2 log10) decrease in viral load (measured as International Units/milliliter) and/or negative Polymerase chain reaction (PCR)-based viral load qualitative result as assessed at visit 2 of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis C, Chronic</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C Virus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with chronic hepatitis C</arm_group_label>
    <description>Na誰ve patients with chronic hepatitis C (CHC) of any genotype will be treated with a standard treatment regimen (pegylated interferon and ribavirin) according to routine clinical practice in Russia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pegylated Interferon</intervention_name>
    <description>Routine treatment with a combination of any pegylated interferon and ribavirin was used according to the label/local practice in Russia.
The treatment course duration complied with the labeled dosage regimen. Each dose of pegylated interferon was administered as a subcutaneous
injection calculated as 1.5 mcg/kg once a week. Therapy duration varied from 24 to 48 weeks depending on Hepatitis C virus (HCV) genotype, viral load, activity and stage of hepatitis C.
The Sponsor did not provide formal drug supply.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with chronic hepatitis C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PegIntron</other_name>
    <other_name>(SCH 54031)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ribavirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Routine treatment with a combination of any pegylated interferon and ribavirin was used according to the label/local practice in Russia.
The treatment course duration complied with the labeled dosage regimen. Ribavirin was taken orally as 200 mg gelatinous capsules. The daily dose varied from 800 to 1200 mg (depending on patient's body weight) twice daily in the
morning and in the evening with meal. Therapy duration varied from 24 to 48 weeks depending on HCV genotype, viral load, activity and stage of hepatitis C.
The Sponsor did not provide formal drug supply.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with chronic hepatitis C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rebetol</other_name>
    <other_name>(SCH 18908)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will include na誰ve patients with chronic hepatitis C (CHC) of any genotype who
        will be treated with a standard treatment regimen (pegylated interferon and ribavirin)
        according to routine clinical practice in Russia.
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Confirmed diagnosis of CHC according to local regulations

          -  Na誰ve Pegylated Interferon (PEG-IFN) CHC patient

          -  No contraindications for PEG-IFN CHC therapy

          -  Negative urine pregnancy test result (for females of childbearing potential)
             documented within the 24-hour period prior to the first dose of study drugs.
             Additionally, all female patients of childbearing potential and all males with female
             partners of childbearing potential must use two forms of effective contraception
             (combined) during treatment and 6 months after treatment end

          -  Willingness to give written informed consent and willingness to participate in and
             comply with the study requirements.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  PEG-IFN treatment in history

          -  Contraindications for PEG-IFN CHC therapy

          -  Females who are pregnant or breast-feeding

          -  Male partners of females who are pregnant

          -  Potentially unreliable participants, and those judged by the investigator to be
             unsuitable for the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 4, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 23, 2008</firstreceived_date>
  <firstreceived_results_date>August 9, 2011</firstreceived_results_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results are available for this study                                           -->
</clinical_study>
